WWW.MY-SUBS.COM
They will keep asking me questions
(that) I don't know the answer to
It's us that have the machine guns
now and it's them that's in the mud
Guns, Mr Shelby.
We'd pay good money.
For who do you speak?
The Irish Republican Army.
What are you? Copper?
GUNSHOT
You went after him
because he was IRA.
I followed him because I thought
he might have information.
The difficulty with undercover work,
Grace, is to remember what you are.
Your sister's in there giving birth.
There's one man who should be here.
You are right, Poll. On my oath.
Tell Freddie it's safe.
Welcome to the world, son.
Freddie.
Pol!
The police came
and took his father away.
You liar!
MUSIC: "Red Right Hand" by
Nick Cave and the Bad Seeds
♪ Take a little walk to the edge of
town and go across the tracks
♪ Where the viaduct looms,
like a bird of doom
♪ As it shifts and cracks
♪ Where secrets lie in the
border fires
♪ In the humming wires
♪ Hey, man, you know
you're never coming back
♪ Past the square, past the bridge,
past the mills, past the stacks
♪ On a gathering storm comes a
tall, handsome man
♪ In a dusty black coat with a
red right hand. ♪
SHE KNOCKS DOOR
Open up, love. I brought more
things for you and the baby.
I've got some fresh eggs and
bread...
I'll leave it here.
BABY CRIES
Ada, think of the little one.
Babies don't have principles.
BABY CRIES
DISTANT SHOUTING
DOOR SLAMS SHUT
Did you speak to her?
She didn't speak back.
Well, did you tell her?
I'll only tell her what
I know to be true.
It's the last time
I am going to say this.
It wasn't me
who shopped Freddie Thorne.
Tommy...
I'd ask you to swear on the Bible,
but you can't swear on that,
can you?
Nothing you hold is sacred.
There's tea.
The new system...
..everything in the diary, eh?
Mm-hm.
A black star? What does that
mean?
The black star day...
..is the day we
take out Billy Kimber and his men.
No-one knows this!
Not even your family?
Grace...
..everyone in my family
hates me. Why would I tell them?
He's off the bloody rails,
is what he is.
If he'll turn nose on his
best mate...
Bloody neighbours, John.
Snitch behind the curtain.
If you think that,
you're the only one who does.
Look at this, look.
Bloody raking it in.
Who's running this carny?
Name of Marston. Intends on wintering
in Smallheath with this ring.
Does he! Ain't he heard nobody in
Smallheath craps in a pot
without the decree of
Tommy Almighty?
Mr Marston, I believe?
The ringmaster?
Proud I am to say so.
Yes, well,
these here are civilised parts.
Man wants to set his stall up with
fellas lamping each other,
he needs himself a licence.
A licence.
For a fee. From those in charge.
I'll tell you what.
How about I keep my money, and you
shove a licence up your arsecrack?
You don't want to speak to me
like that.
And who the bloody hell do
you think you are?
My name is Arthur Shelby.
Dad?
Jesus.
Thank you. You are a good boy.
Bless you, Father, for these
bounties we are about to receive...
Jesus Christ...
Please, woman...
..not in vain.
Finish your sandwich
and sling your hook.
Pollyanna.
I'm the guest of the head
of this family,
so why don't you tend
to your mangle or your scuttle?
The head of the family ain't here.
Tommy...he sometimes helps me
with business.
Ah. Well. Speak of the devil.
How are you, son?
Get out.
Come on, son. I'm a changed man.
This family needed you ten years ago
when you walked out on it.
Not now. Get out of this house.
Tommy, he's different...
You shut up.
It's all right, son.
Arthur Shelby never stays where
he is not welcome.
Quite something you've become.
Bye, son.
He's our dad.
He's a selfish bastard.
You calling someone a selfish
bastard?
That's a bit rich, Tommy.
I mean, thanks to you...
..we're already down a bloody
sister.
If you want to see him, Arthur...
You want to see him?
You can go with him.
Grace...
I am taking five pounds
from petty cash all right?
We don't have five pounds in
petty cash.
Then I'll take what we've got.
Count it and leave a receipt.
Arthur, there are some things in the
books that I don't understand.
Likewise. Every week we pay
one pound and ten shillings
by postal order to a "Daniel Owen"
in London.
Danny Whizz Bang, hangs round the
pubs in Camden Town Wharf for us.
He keeps his ears open for business.
He's a good man.
I thought Danny Whizz Bang was dead.
Then you thought wrong, didn't you?
But I've seen his grave.
He was shot.
That was a show to satisfy the wops.
Tommy just shot some
sheep's brains at him.
Who is buried in his grave?
Now look, Grace, if you know what's
good for you,
you don't ask questions about things
that don't concern you.
Never. Right!
And that's for you.
And don't tell Tommy I took this.
The boy needs a hiding,
if you ask me.
Yeah, well, Aunt Polly's close to
giving him one.
John and Ada too, it sounds like.
John moans on bloody principle -
but if you saw his Mrs...
You have a girl yourself, son?
P'raps when it suits Tommy, eh?
Yeah, well...
..he's been different, you know,
since the war.
Yeah, well...
the war can change a man.
Speaking for myself, anyway.
Where did you fight, Dad?
All over, son, all over.
Yeah, all over.
Then the salvation of Jesus Christ
spread his light over me,
and, as a pilgrim,
I come to visit the New World...
America.
..where I beheld the future.
Casinos!
Money factories, son.
Look, I've been studying
the competition,
their schemes, their systems.
Look at that...
Show me.
It's all there.
There's a fortune to be made here.
I'm an old man, and my heart's a
battered vessel. But within...
..there still beats the
fluttering pulse of a dream...
The Shelby Casino and Hotel...
Gents and dames will come
flocking from all corners -
New York, Chicago, Boston -
to The Shelby, where I can stand
proudly
with my dear children by my side.
And the women there!
Like fresh peaches.
Thou could have a dozen.
We'd all of us be kings!
How much, how much to get started?
The oak needs but an acorn.
Let's do it.
Let's bloody do it.
It would make my heart beam...
but I don't want to cause
any discord between the brothers.
So, please, why don't you talk to
Tommy first...?
I'm sick of taking orders from him.
Tommy's not the only one in the
family with a head for business,
and Shelby money is Shelby money.
I thank God for my wonderful sons.
This is cause for a celebration!
Yeah. Slange. Slange.
On your feet, soldier!
On your feet.
Dad, I don't want to fight you, Dad.
Come on, boy!
I'm old enough to be thy father.
Hit him! Hit him! That's it! Hit him!
On your feet.
Get up.
All right!
That's it!
Is that all you've got, boy?
Get up.
This here is Arthur Shelby Junior!
My son.
I love him, and I'm proud of him,
and he can fight
any one of yous in here.
CHEERING AND APPLAUSE
You did good, son. You did good.
I love you, Dad. I love you.
Mr Shelby?
Who's asking?
My name is Byrne.
I had word from your man in Camden
Town that you wanted to parley.
Then parley it is.
A few months ago a man named Ryan
came to this place with
a view to buying some
goods from you.
Mr Ryan met with an accident.
He was shot.
I heard... He was a man with a
quick mouth. I know that.
I wondered
if he had made any enemies in here.
None that I know of.
It's not the kind of place
to make enemies.
All are welcome here, Mr Byrne...
Including Irish?
Especially Irish.
Ryan told you he was a member
of the Irish Republican Army.
Was he still welcome?
Like I say,
any man that buys beer is welcome.
Perhaps you didn't believe him.
In pubs sometimes people say things
and sometimes it's
the whisky talking.
It's hard to tell which is which.
As a teetotal man I find it amusing.
Except when it ends in tragedy.
Would you like some cordial
and water, Mr Byrne?
You see, Mr Shelby, Ryan,
for all his quick mouth,
was indeed connected.
Very well connected...to our
brotherhood.
By membership and blood.
He was my cousin.
I am from South Armagh.
I am a man of influence there.
Cordial and water would be grand,
Mr Shelby.
Grace. Bring some water
and cordial to the snug.
Yes, Mr Shelby.
My cousin came to buy guns.
And I told him I had none.
Your man Danny Owen talks a lot
when he's drunk.
He says the Peaky Blinders
do have the guns.
Robbed from the factory
down the road.
He boasts about a stack of
Lewis machine guns.
And enough belts of ammunition to
hold up God's trousers.
Yep. That sounds like our Danny.
He has an imagination.
Like I said, sometimes it's the
whisky that does the talking.
He says only the brothers
know where the guns are kept.
Well, Danny also says he sees
German infantrymen on the backs
of milk carts. And he shoots them
with his broomstick.
We have men in the BSA factory.
They say it's you who has them.
And we have men who
work in the police station.
Every finger, Mr Shelby,
every finger in this city,
points in one direction.
Please don't mistake me for a fool.
Let me get to the point.
I don't care what kind of
half-arsed tinker operation
you have going here.
But I can assure you,
I represent a very different
category of organization.
My cousin was shot.
I am judge, jury and executioner.
I find you guilty
and I pass sentence.
You deliver the guns to me
or I deliver death and hell's fury
to you and your little tribe of
heathens.
Am I making myself clear?
Let me confess something to you.
And only to you.
I have the guns...
..but they have become
a burden to me.
Perhaps it is time
to unload that burden.
For the right price.
CHATTERING
MAN CLEARS THROAT
Malachi Byrne.
Brigade commander of
the South Armagh IRA.
You've hooked yourself
a big fish there.
With these guns as bait who knows
what we'll catch?
'We'?
Are you suggesting that you and I
could work together as a team?
Perhaps we have more in common than
you think, Inspector.
Can you deliver him?
With your help.
And I want word put out in Ireland
that I was not involved.
So, I would be solving
a problem for you.
And I would be winning you
that medal.
If I get a medal I will have your
initials engraved on the backside.
My initials on your backside.
Now, that's quite an image.
Inspector, since we are getting
along so well,
can you answer me a question?
Who gave you Freddie Thorne?
As everyone in the city knows.
It was you, Mr Shelby.
KNOCKS ON DOOR
MUSIC: "Ball and Biscuit" by
The White Stripes
Hello, son.
It's all there.
It is indeed.
We're going to build something with
this, son. Something magnificent.
When do we sail, Dad?
Hungry for work, are you?
Yeah.
A ship sails Friday.
Meet me at the boxing ring.
Right. Friday.
Friday.
KNOCKS ON DOOR
KNOCKS CONTINUE
Leave that open.
No.
Are you expecting trouble?
Yeah.
At this hour?
Midnight is as good an hour as any.
What the hell is going on?
When the St Andrew's bell strikes
midnight,
two IRA men are going to come
through that door.
When they have what they want,
they plan to kill me.
It's your job to stop that
happening.
You could have given me
some warning.
I just got the message myself.
They want to meet me here alone.
And barmaids don't count?
No. Barmaids don't count.
Now, you're going to be in the
back room.
I am going to be sitting there.
When I make a toast, you're going to
come out with that thing raised.
You don't shoot, you just point,
I'll do the rest.
Will you kill them?
No, the police want them alive...
The police know about this?
Look, you just hold it up
and you just point. Right?
BELL BEGINS TO RING
Right, go, go. Go on, go.
BELL TOLLS MIDNIGHT
We'll hold back here.
If damage is done to either side,
it's no concern of ours.
BELL CONTINUES TO TOLL
Lost your thirst, eh?
Just show us where.
Give me the cash.
You're going to need a shovel.
HE LAUGHS
You thick fucking tinker.
Did you think we'd let you live?
Make your peace, Mr Shelby.
I will make my peace my own way.
To barmaids who don't count...
Why did you shoot?
Why did you shoot, Grace?
I didn't know I had it
in me like that.
So, now you've seen me.
And you've seen me...
..and I'm sorry.
You were supposed to come
on the sixth chime.
on the fucking sixth chime.
They refused to surrender.
They fought well.
They were brave men.
Well, he looks like he was
killed by a wild fucking animal.
Still...
This never happened and they were
never here, who cares?
Will you get the bodies out of here.
All right, are they...? Are they
making the lady uncomfortable?
I'll leave you
two love birds to it then, eh?
Thank you.
I'm sorry.
First of all, let me
say I had no idea he would
involve you in this ugly business.
If I had,
I never would have let it happen.
He trusts me. I told you that.
You didn't believe me.
Sergeant Moss made a report.
Which, of course, I have burnt.
He said that when he entered
the room, you were embracing.
Is that your primary concern?
An embrace?
My...my concern is your welfare.
It was me who killed them.
I had no control.
You have been living with beasts.
It was the beast that
tried to stop me.
I believe last night
something inside me changed.
I no longer feel
the need to avenge my father.
The hatred that I brought with me
here has gone.
And therefore my reasons for joining
the service.
You want to resign?
I think our mission has come
to a natural end.
I think I know where the
guns are hidden.
You do? So? Tell me where.
If I am right,
and the guns are found,
you will have no more business
with Thomas Shelby.
Is that not so?
Our military mission will be over.
And we can leave
the city as we found it.
Are you trying to...
do a deal with me?
Because if you are,
you must be explicit.
I want your word that
Thomas Shelby will not be harmed
if the guns are recovered.
Your word as a gentleman.
Will you give it?
Why...would you want to save him?
A residue of sympathy.
Sympathy? You mean sentiment?
Yes.
In his way, he has been kind to me.
Sentiment.
Yes.
You are too
good-hearted for this work.
Perhaps.
So, for my sake,
will you spare him?
You have my word.
A week after the robbery there was a
burial at St Andrews' churchyard.
I have found out the man supposed
to be buried is alive.
Arthur is quite transparent.
I learned that the funeral was
attended only by the brothers.
And the grave that was dug was
far deeper than your average
and was lined with lead...
..to keep out the damp.
The guns are buried in that grave.
Then, tonight,
we will dig up the grave.
♪ When my family thinks
that I'm safely in my bed
♪ Oh, from morn until night
♪ I am stretched out at your head
♪ Calling out unto the earth
♪ With tears hot and wild
♪ For the loss of a boy
♪ That I loved as a child... ♪
Please, please go to sleep.
♪ So, I am stretched on your grave
♪ And I'll lie here for ever
♪ If your hands were in mine
♪ I'd be sure they would not sever
♪ My apple tree, my brightness
♪ It's time we were together... ♪
Well done, boys!
♪ For I smell of the earth
♪ And I'm worn by the weather. ♪
All, but one gun accounted for.
Then, Sir, I resign my commission.
Good.
So, I am no longer your
superior officer and
you are no longer my subordinate.
And therefore...
..regulations permit me...
to offer you this.
I am...I am a simple man,
but a good man.
And my admiration for you...
..has turned to love.
I don't ask for love in return.
Just...
..recognition that we are
like minds...
..with shared values.
Grace...
..will you marry me?
Mr Campbell...
..you deserve better.
Is it him between us?
Is it the beast that dug that grave?
Is it him?
My resignation will be with
you in the morning...
WHISTLE BLOWS
Dad!
Hullo, son.
May I ask who gave my whereabouts?
Marston.
Said you left him last night with
a bill for your whores.
Well, at least
we got to say goodbye, son.
And bid a fond adieu to your
dear brothers, would you?
How...how could you do this to us?
Do what, son?
All that stuff you said
about...the Shelby Casino...
..and Atlantic City.
Well, if the truth be told,
I've not been
so acquainted with that promised
land as I had thee believe.
You're a fucking liar and a thief.
You give me back my fucking money.
"Do not despise the thief,
if he steals to
"satisfy his starvation"
That's in the Holy Bible, son.
And I've starved for so very long.
Fare thee well, son.
I waited for you.
I waited.
Listen to me, boy.
You are not in the prize ring now.
If you ever put your hands on me
again,
I'll cut your fucking throat
and spread you on these tracks.
DOOR OPENS
Where's your father?
I'm assuming he's busy frittering
the 500 you took from us
and put in his thieving,
whore-groping hands.
What were you thinking?
How dare you do something like that
without talking to Thomas or me?
Does Tommy know?
No. But you're going to tell him.
You might take
satisfaction in a great victory.
A terrible consequence has been
avoided.
'Those guns that we dug up will
never be used to murder the innocent
'or usurp the status quo.
'But, even though we have solved a
crime,
'we have as yet failed to
punish the criminal.'
This man who dug that grave has
also dug his own.
He has proved himself a deadly
menace to the King's peace.
'And tonight we will strike
him down.
'We will drive our swords
through his black heart,
'we will pursue him into the
rat holes that he infests.'
And, finally,
we will rid this city of his kind.
Justice will be done and will be
seen to be done.
Amen.
There's going to be trouble now,
Finn.
You look after yourself,
do you hear me?
I'm going to be going away for a
while. Right... Go on.
Right... Who wants to fucking fight?
Fighting's over.
We're closing up and moving on.
I said who wants to fucking fight?
My name is Arthur fucking Shelby!
Who dares to fight me?!
Go home, lad. Before you catch
yourself a spanking.
My brother in Digbeth just says
the police are coming down
from Deritend in numbers.
Asking for Tommy Shelby by name.
Shit.
I'm going to have to lie low
for a while. Why?
I lost my bargaining power.
This copper, it's just me
and him now.
When I get back...
..I'll tell you some things.
Harry said the police
are already in Digbeth.
Yeah. You took a chance
coming here, why?
The police are in the lane, Tommy.
Come with me.
HE SLAMS THE GUN DOWN
I'm looking
for Thomas Shelby.
Never heard of him.
You'll never find him.
Go home.
Perhaps I should ask
the question again.
On your knees.
Now, understand this, barman.
I don't care if you live or die.
I don't know.
He left...
..with the barmaid.
He left with Grace.
I think they were going to
her place.
Call it off.
I don't understand, sir.
We should find the barmaid...
Call it all off!
All of it!
Get in.
It's not much of a place.
It's all right.
You want tea?
Tea? No.
I have rum...
Actually, tea it is.
You want to impress me?
Yes. And do you have a biscuit?
No. They attract mice.
People look different at home.
In what way?
Off guard.
Should I be on my guard?
No, I'm a man who drinks tea.
When the trouble dies down, I'll go.
When will it die down, do you think?
Late, I would say.
So, not until the morning then.
Yes. I'd say I'll be here
till morning.
You have a gramophone?
It's broken.
We could still dance.
Yes. Why not.
I know you like to be asked
properly.
Grace, can I have this dance?
Are you OK?
I don't hear
the shovels against the wall.
What shovels?
Will you help me?
Help you with what?
With everything...
..the whole fucking thing.
Fucking life...
..business.
I've found you.
And you found me.
We'll help each other.
MUSIC: "Time"
by Tom Waits
♪ Well, the smart money's on Harlow
♪ And the moon is in the street
♪ And the shadow boys are breaking
all the laws
♪ And you're east of East Saint Louis
and the wind is making speeches
♪ And the rain sounds like a round
of applause
♪ And Napoleon is weeping in a
carnival saloon
♪ His invisible fiancee's
in the mirror... ♪
HE SOBS
♪ And the band is going home,
♪ It's raining hammers,
it's raining nails
♪ And it's true there's nothing
left for him down here.
♪ And it's time, time, time...
♪ And it's time, time, time... ♪
Our Father, who art in heaven.
Hallowed be thy name....
♪ And they all pretend
they're orphans
♪ And their memory's like a train
♪ You can see it getting
smaller as it pulls away
♪ And the things you can't remember
♪ Tell the things you can't forget
♪ That history puts a saint in
every dream
♪ Well, she said she'd
stick around... ♪
HE GASPS AND BREATHES
HE COUGHS AND SOBS
♪ So, close your eyes, son,
and this won't hurt a bit... ♪
PHONE RINGS
Send a telegram to Mr Churchill...
I have news, very good news.
Tell him the business
I came to attend to is now complete.
'I'll be leaving the city.
'There's just one matter
I need to tidy up first.'
♪ And it's time, time, time
that you love
♪ And it's time, time, time...
DOOR OPENS
Polly told you?
Yep.
You should have used a gun.
Are you laughing at me, Tommy?
Yeah.
Just when things are starting to go
right, Arthur...
you try and do this.
Don't you like fancy parties?
Or, um...
..champagne or fast cars?
Or how about this...?
Your name
on a business card.
Shelby...
..Brothers Limited.
Arthur Shelby.
Associate bookmaker.
I just had them picked
up from the printers this morning.
You're one of three
shareholders.
Me, you and John, and according to
the law, we are equal partners...
and it's written on the paperwork
in black and white.
A third, a third, a third.
But the thing is...
well, me and John quite fancy
splitting your share so,
just next time, use a gun, man.
Our men at the station tell me
that copper is leaving town.
We're in the clear.
We are on our way up
in the world, brother.
Believe me.
MUSIC: "Bring It On"
by Nick Cave
♪ This garden that I built for you
♪ That you sit in now and yearn
♪ I will never leave it, dear
♪ I could not bear to return
♪ And find it all untended
♪ With the trees all bended low
♪ This garden is our home, dear
♪ And I got nowhere else to go
♪ So, bring it on
♪ Bring it on
♪ Every little tear
♪ Bring it on, every useless fear
♪ Bring it on, all your
shattered dreams
♪ And I'll scatter them
into the sea
♪ Bring it on
♪ Get it on
♪ Yeah, bring it on
♪ Every little tear
♪ And I'll make them disappear. ♪