WWW.MY-SUBS.COM
I'll be in London one week,
at this address.
Finish your business here
and join me.
'Dear Grace...
'Before the war, when I had
an important decision to make,
'I used to flip a coin.
'Perhaps that is what
I will do again.'
♪ I've lain with the devil
♪ Cursed God above
♪ Forsaken heaven
♪ To bring you my love
♪ To bring you my love. ♪
THEME: "Red Right Hand"
by Nick Cave & The Bad Seeds
♪ Take a little walk
to the edge of town
♪ And go across the tracks
♪ Where the viaduct looms
Like a bird of doom
♪ As it shifts and cracks
♪ Where secrets lie
in the border fires
♪ In the humming wires
♪ Hey man, you know
you're never coming back
♪ Past the square
Past the bridge
♪ Past the mills
Past the stacks
♪ On a gathering storm
comes a tall, handsome man
♪ In a dusty black coat
♪ With a red right hand. ♪
..and give him peace. Amen.
Amen.
I promised my friend
Freddie Thorne
that I'd say a few words
over his grave
if he should pass before me.
I made this promise before
he became me brother-in-law -
when we were in France,
fighting for the King.
Amen.
And in the end it wasn't war
that took Freddie.
Pestilence took him.
Come here.
But Freddie passed on his soul
and his spirit to a new generation
before he was cruelly taken.
We thought, now Freddie's gone,
you might come back to Birmingham.
God, do you know how funny it is
that you've got
chauffeurs in uniform now?
It's just for the occasion, Ada.
Do you know how unfair it is
that you've got four Bugattis
when half the country's starving?
So now they've made you
ashamed of us, eh?
Sometimes when I think how I used
to be, it makes me embarrassed.
Karl's with his cousins.
I caught 'em trying
to pinch flowers off a grave.
Ada, are you coming home?
I'm going home.
It's all right, Poll.
We make Ada embarrassed.
That's not what I said.
There's another reason
we want you home.
We're planning an expansion.
I'm taking premises in London...
~ Tommy, it's a funeral,
business can wait. ~ Polly,
if Ada was weeping then I'd stop.
But she's not.
The expansion means
it's going to be dangerous
to be a Shelby in London
for a while.
Yeah, well,
I'm not a Shelby anymore.
And I'm not a Thorne now, either.
I'm free.
I've got to get Karl home.
I told you. Let me do it.
It's all right.
I'll have some men watch her house
till the danger passes.
"Till the danger passes"?
That'll be the bloody day.
It happened at exactly 7am.
Nobody saw anything.
Our patrols were not in the area.
Mr Shelby, have you got
any idea who might've done it?
I'd say it was something
to do with the gas.
It's just been fitted.
Madam, the structure's
not yet declared safe.
Madam!
This is all over the place.
Confetti.
You can go.
Right.
Who?
Who did this to us?
Whisky. Irish.
I heard there was a bit of a bang
in your part of town.
Gas and electric don't mix.
Who'd have thought
they would, eh?
How's business otherwise,
Mr Shelby?
You know something?
In these times of hunger
and hardship,
business is surprisingly good.
Which one of you is
the Peaky Blinder devil?
Gentlemen.
♪ I drank some dirty water
♪ Shook evil hands
♪ I done some bad things
♪ They get easier to do
♪ And then I wrote a nasty letter
♪ And I sent it to the Lord
♪ I said, "Don't you dare
come and bother me no more"
♪ Oh
♪ Oh, oh, oh
♪ Oh, oh, oh... ♪
Finn! Get in here.
Finn! Hold the phone. Come here.
~ Take the odds. ~ Yeah, sure.
Polly.
Did he say who did it?
He's gone to the Black Lion.
On his own?
Tommy does everything on his own.
~ Should I go to the Black Lion?
~ What?
~ Should I go there and see him? ~ No.
Where the fuck is Arthur?
Protecting the Garrison's
whisky from the police.
For fuck's sake!
Polly, it feels a little bit to me
like things are getting out of hand.
So get 'em in hand.
Do you know what Ada said to me
this morning?
She said we all look like we work
in a factory under the ground.
She said we look like ghosts.
She'll be back.
When?
When she needs us.
And anyway, who the fuck
would blow up our pub?
~ Six. ~ Six what?
Six questions since
you walked through the door.
Soon you're going to have to start
being the man with the answers.
Why?
Seven.
Because when London happens,
you'll have to hold up your end
or we'll find somebody else who can.
Thomas Shelby.
You blew up my pub.
Anger defeats fear, good.
Tommy has a reputation to uphold.
A reputation for not being
scared of anything.
In all the world, violent men
are the easiest to deal with.
So tell me, which brand
of rebel are you, eh?
I read somewhere that you Paddies
started fighting
amongst yourselves, now.
The King offers you a peace treaty
and you start a war about it.
That's funny, don't you think?
A war about peace.
So are you for the treaty
or against the treaty?
Forgive me, I get confused.
You are one decision away
from death, Mr Shelby.
So stop fucking smiling.
Your name is Irene O'Donnell.
You have a son at the
Cherry Wood Road School in Harborne.
He has irons on his legs,
his name is Sean,
he comes last
in every race, poor boy.
Poor boy if the race was important.
Do you know what I mean,
Irene O'Donnell?
There are other ways of
carrying out this mission.
Please allow me to put a bullet
in this scum tinker's head.
No.
He researches his enemies,
that's why he's been chosen.
I am chosen?
I'm chosen.
Can the chosen one smoke?
A vacancy has appeared
and you're going to fill it.
Chosen by whom?
By an informed consensus.
I have things to do.
So perhaps you could tell
the chosen one
what he's been chosen for.
From now on, Mr Shelby,
you shut your fucking Gypsy mouth
and listen to your instructions.
Fuck!
I need the area round
the co-operative stables
clear of coppers between
midnight and four tonight.
Right. Could I ask why?
Well, whatever it is you're
going to do, don't start any fires.
The firemen go out
on strike at midnight.
That's all. You can go.
I've got some information
you might be interested in.
No charge.
There's an old friend of ours
coming back to the city.
Just passing through, he says.
He's very grand these days.
He's head of some
secret department -
the Irish Desk.
So I doubt he'll be bothering
with the likes of us, eh?
I'll say good night, Tom.
I want to speak to a representative!
Father! Father!
It was the Ulsterman,
the man with the wolf head!
Get the fuck off me!
You must reconcile yourself
with the fate that awaits.
I demand to speak to
a representative
of His Majesty the King!
Make your peace with God.
A representative of
His Majesty the King!
~ Father. ~ Come on.
Where are you going?
Does someone here have
business with the King?
Major Campbell.
About time.
I am a very busy man, Governor.
In seven and a half minutes,
the man in that cell
is due to be hanged for murder.
The murder of an Irish activist
in Whitechapel.
Does the case ring any bells,
Major Campbell?
No, Governor,
I hear no bells.
Since yesterday morning,
he's been claiming that the murder
was ordered
by the British
Secret Intelligence Service.
It's a little late to be coming up
with nonsense like that,
don't you think?
He was told if he kept
his mouth shut
there would be a last-minute pardon,
which has not materialised.
Forgive me, Governor,
but what business is this of mine?
He says the man who hired him
was an Intelligence Service
Chief of Staff,
an Ulsterman.
Carries a cane
with a wolf-head handle,
a bullet wound in his right leg.
No...
Still no bells. Governor...
..you have a very clear remit.
Part of that remit is
to oversee the smooth completion
of executions
sanctioned by the Crown.
And in the next four minutes it is
your duty to escort that man...
..to the gates of hell.
Is that clear?
And...if you should ever have
the desire
to discuss this matter
with anyone else...
..I know where you live.
Arthur,
Tommy's called a family meeting.
Arthur!
He just beat the shit out of
an apprentice.
I had to take half the kid away
in buckets.
Arthur!
2,000.
Come on.
Sit down, Finn.
~ Where the bloody hell is Tommy?
~ He's on his way.
All right then,
while we're waiting patiently...
Whisky - left over from
the explosion.
It's good stuff, as well.
Right...
Before Tommy gets here,
I think there's a few things
we need to get straight
between the rest of us.
YOU think?
Yeah.
Yeah, I do. I want to know...
..when did we all take a vote
on this expansion south?
If you have anything to say,
you wait for Thomas.
Polly's fucking right.
I see all the books.
Legal and off track.
Sort of stuff you don't see.
And in the past year
the Shelby Company Limited
has been making £150...
a day.
Right? A fucking day.
Sometimes more.
So what I want to know
is why are we changing things?
Polly, look what's happened already.
We haven't even set foot
in London yet
and they've already blown up
our fucking pub.
~ Who said anything
about cockneys? ~ Who else?
Do you know who did it, do you?
No, she doesn't know who did it.
I'm told only family
are allowed to speak.
Everyone's allowed to speak.
On your feet, Esme,
let's hear what you have to say.
I speak for our household.
~ So... ~ John, this company
is a modern enterprise
and believes in
equal rights for women.
On your feet, Esme.
I'm not a blood member
of this family
but perhaps, indeed,
because I'm NOT a member
I can see things
in a different light.
So I'll get to my point.
That would be nice.
As my husband said,
Shelby Company Limited
is now very successful.
But London...
I have kin in Shepherd's Bush
and Portobello.
It's more like wars
between armies down there.
And the coppers fight
side-by-side with them.
And there are foreigners
of every description...
..and the use of bombs
is the least of it.
I have a child,
blessed with the Shelby family
good looks.
I want John to see him grow up.
I want us to someday live somewhere
with fresh air and trees
and keep chickens or something.
But London is just smoke
and trouble, Thomas.
"Thomas"?
That's all I have to say.
That was a lot of words,
a lot of words.
Wash them down with a nice drink.
Thank you, Esme.
Firstly, the bang in the pub
was nothing to do with London.
Understood?
The bang is something
I'm dealing with on my own.
Secondly, we've nothing to fear
from the proposed business expansion
so long as we stick together.
And after the first few weeks,
nine tenths of what we do in London
will be legal.
The other tenth is in good hands.
Isn't that right, Arthur?
That's right.
Now, some of you in this room
have expressed their reservations.
Fair enough.
Any of you who want no part
in the future of this company,
walk out the door...
..right now.
Go raise your chickens.
For those of you with ambition...
..the expansion process
begins tomorrow.
Tomorrow?
I'm company treasurer,
you should speak to me first.
It's Newmarket tomorrow,
third busiest day of the year.
We have 18 staff.
Who you trust with 200 quid takings?
Oh, I changed the combination.
So what's going on, Thomas?
Who'd you meet at the Black Lion?
Give me the combination, Polly.
Polly, give me the combination!
What happened to the pub
is Irish business.
We're in a situation where,
for everyone's safety,
it's best if some things
remain undisclosed.
So why tomorrow?
Like you say,
tomorrow's Newmarket.
All the London bosses
will be at the races.
What, so you just roll up
and take the city?
No, we take the opportunity
to show our hand.
The Italian gangs
and the Jewish gangs
have been at war in London
for six months.
It's not our war.
The Jews have been having
the worst of it. They need allies.
~ Yeah, but we don't.
~ We need a foothold
at the southern end
of the Grand Union.
The Jews control Camden Town.
Your mother said,
"It's his cleverness
that'll kill him."
No-one gets killed, Polly.
We go down tomorrow when it's quiet
and we leave our message.
If Alfie Solomon
and his Camden boys come to us,
we'll negotiate the use
of a secure bonded warehouse
and then our legal activities
in London can begin.
Now please, open the fucking safe.
Do you know, it was a fine speech
you made in there...
..about this company believing
in equal rights for women.
But when it comes to it,
you don't listen to a word we say.
Maybe you don't trust us.
She was one woman, Thomas.
Well, maybe it's time
you forgot about her.
Forgot about who?
You and the boys,
go and get yourselves killed.
Are you going to London now?
No, there's something
I have to do first.
Oh, I've got a typewriter like that.
I got it out of a catalogue.
I'm doing a correspondence course.
I'm learning to do it
with my eyes shut.
It's a test you have to do.
Will you come back before you go?
No.
I wish, just once,
you wouldn't pay me,
as if we were ordinary people.
Yeah.
Let's begin.
Hands on the table.
Tonight we have two
new pilgrims joining us.
So, let's welcome them.
Starting with you.
Who is it that
you're seeking to reach?
My husband.
He was taken six months ago
by the influenza.
I tried to reach him through
Mrs Breach at Sparkhill
but she kept getting
his middle name wrong.
Don't talk about Mrs Breach
in this house.
She's an un-sanctified charlatan.
And you?
Who do you seek?
Well, the truth...
Sorry, the truth is,
I'm not even sure she's dead.
So I came here to find out.
Er...
You see, my son and my daughter
were taken from me
when they were very small -
taken by the parish authorities.
And I never knew
what happened to them.
But lately...
I've had a feeling.
Like, a feeling...
I can't put it into words.
And I keep having a dream.
I see a pretty girl,
about 18 years old.
And she's standing
across the street...
..and she tells me
she's passed over.
Now, my daughter
would have been 18 this year.
On May 15th.
And this girl has dark eyes
like mine.
And she shouts...and shouts.
And she tells me
she wants to talk to me
because I'm her mother.
Now, I don't even know
what name they gave her
after they stole her from me.
But if she does want
to say goodbye...
I thought this would be the place.
You're wearing the Black Madonna.
You're Gypsy?
The part of me that dreams is Gypsy.
My maiden name is Shelby.
So...
..perhaps you could do me first.
No!
NO!
No...
♪ But if you come
♪ And all the flowers are dying
♪ And I am dead
♪ As dead I well may be
♪ You'll come and find
♪ The place where I am lying
♪ And kneel and say
♪ An "Ave" there for me
♪ And I will know
♪ Though soft ye tread above me
♪ And then my grave
♪ Will richer, sweeter be
♪ And you'll bend down
♪ And tell me that you love me
♪ And I will rest in peace
♪ Until you come to me. ♪
Eamonn Duggan?
All right, Tommy's here.
Hang on!
John!
I'm coming!
7 o'clock, 12 o'clock,
10 if I'm still sober.
I got it from the doctor -
it keeps me nice and calm.
Same thing they gave us
in the trenches
to stop us fucking wanking.
Polly said it's good for me temper.
~ It slows me down, Tom. ~ Arthur...
there are some things
Polly doesn't understand.
I need you fast. Not slow, eh?
She wouldn't let go
of my fucking leg.
~ I bet that's not all
she wouldn't let go of! ~ Right.
You know she's against this, Tom.
She's got opinions.
Nothing wrong with opinions, John.
~ Get in the fucking car. ~ Shut up!
Right!
The Peaky Blinders are going
on fucking holiday!
Sit down, you mad bastard.
You're against this
the same as me, aren't you?
Look out for anyone putting
big money on Divine Star
in the 3:30 at Newmarket.
She's one of ours.
Anything over £1, tell me.
Polly...
I don't wish to pry
into your business
but you should know something.
That woman is a trickster.
What woman?
Her sister was in
the wash house early,
boasting there'd been
a Shelby at the table.
What woman?
Gypsies talk to each other.
You went to see Mrs Price
in the Patch last night.
I'm sorry...
So what do you know?
I know they push the glass.
The man, it's her cousin.
He pushes the glass.
It's a trick.
They tell you what
you already believe.
She set up after the war
because of all the widows.
Polly, I just thought
you should know.
And in this fucking wash house,
did they tell you why I went there?
You tell a soul in this family,
and I swear I will cut you.
I don't need a knife to stop me
telling secrets given in confidence.
It is a matter of honour.
Look at this! Look.
I love it.
Your Esme was right
about one thing -
you can't beat the countryside.
You know, I think I want
to live in the country one day...
..and keep chickens.
Yeah, we'll see you
in London, Arthur.
~ Oh, for fuck's sake! ~ Take these.
We need to bury him.
Who the fuck is that?
It's Irish business.
I thought it best
if I deal with it on my own.
Come on, we did a thousand
of these in France.
John, grab his head.
So, we're not really
going to London?
Once we bury him,
then the holiday begins.
Much obliged.
It's a fucking freak show.
What the fuck is that racket?
~ This is what they call music
these days, brother. ~ Music?!
Oi!
Oi! Put it away.
Fuck off!
Fucking look at this spot, eh?
It's all right, isn't it?
Irish whisky - a bottle.
And hurry up!
Fucking hell,
I recognise a few of these lads.
That's Sabini's cousin, over there.
That's right, Arthur,
it's Sabini's club.
Jesus Christ,
everybody in here's a fucking face.
Just the lieutenants, John.
No sign of the officers.
Right, let's line them up.
Holiday!
Gentlemen, there's been a mistake.
I'm afraid you're going to
have to leave.
We just bought a fucking bottle.
Some of the men here recognise you
from the racetracks in the north.
Yeah, we get that a lot.
They say you have no business
coming south of the line
without prior agreement.
And what line would that be,
my friend?
They say this is provocation.
Right, well, you tell them
we're on holiday.
You're breaking the rules.
They say you are
the Peaky Blinders...
Peaky scum!
Who the fuck's next?
Come here!
Put some ice on 'em!
Get out.
Yeah?
Are you going to use that?
Didn't think so.
We came here...
not to make enemies...
No!
We came here to make new friends.
Those of you who are last
will soon be first.
And those of you who are downtrodden
will rise up.
Yip.
You know where to find us.
I think I've lost a tooth.
I'll have none left at this rate!
Some fucking holiday this is.
Yeah? You all right without
your fucking medicine, Arthur?
~ Here, this'll fix you. ~ Give me that!
You, John boy...eh? How are you?
~ Or should I ask your fucking wife?
~ Oh, give over!
No more talk of chickens,
do you hear me?
Fuck the chickens.
I've 50 quid in me pocket.
Let's paint the town, eh?
Come.
~ Oh, dear God! ~ Good Lord,
I assumed it was Betty with tea.
Forgive me, sir, but your secretary
was not at the desk.
No, because she takes lunch -
like normal people.
And you can turn around,
this lady is
a professional life model.
She does this for a living.
I'm more than happy
to come back later, sir.
No, no, no. Later on
I'm in the house. Just, erm...
..keep your back turned,
if you must.
I would guess you haven't been
exposed to Bohemian society, Major?
Well, I...I...play cards on occasion.
You're a stranger to cocaine
and exotic dancing, too, I imagine.
I find the more obvious vices
the easiest to resist.
It's the sneaky little obscure ones
that bring you to your knees, yes?
So what business is so urgent
it trumps lunch?
Well, sir, our man in Birmingham
has passed his first test
with flying colours.
Oh, I'm horrible at faces.
So I think we can begin to
prepare him for the bigger task.
~ Expressions elude me,
I think too much. ~ Sir?
I need your authority
to proceed with all urgency
in preparing the new man
for the bigger task.
You're talking about
your bookmaker.
Yes, sir.
You have a history with this man.
Why did you choose him?
To apply pressure on a man
for this type of work
you have to know his weaknesses
and I know this man's weaknesses
intimately.
And after "mission accomplished",
do we trust him
to keep his mouth shut?
Absolutely not, sir.
So when he's served his purpose,
he will be consigned to history
in exactly the same way
as his predecessor.
You mean at the end of a rope?
Well, the end of the rope
has been this man's destiny
since the night he was born.
You're early.
Shut your eyes, Lizzie.
What?
Shut your eyes.
Go on, shut your eyes.
Good.
Now, come with me.
No, shut your eyes!
~ This way. ~ What are you doing, Tom?
You've got to sit down
here. Right...
Sit down. Now, OK...
~ Type this. ~ Why?
Lizzie, type this.
"If wi..." Put your cigarette down.
Right. "If winter comes..."
"..then can spring be far behind?"
Why?! Did you say spring?
Lizzie, what comes after winter?
Let's see.
That's a question.
Where's the question mark?
Put in the question mark.
Now type this.
"Wanted - secretary
for expanding business."
Slow down!
"Must be able to take dictation
and touch-type."
"Five days a week.
"Eight pounds
and four shillings a month.
"Must be able to start immediately."
Are you serious?
Things are starting
to happen, Lizzie.
I need someone who can
look the other way sometimes.
And you can stop
the other work too, Lizzie.
All of it this time.
No exceptions.
Eight o'clock, Monday morning,
the upstairs office.
Don't be late.
Newmarket was profitable.
Arthur told me
how you left your message.
And when I asked him
where his medicine was,
he said you poured it away.
All I poured away was opium
and bromide.
Oh, that's how it works
in London, isn't it?
Every boss has to have
a mad dog at his side.
Yeah, somebody who can't be
predicted, somebody mad in the head.
But Thomas Shelby
uses his own brother.
~ Stop fucking fighting me!
~ Somebody has to.
That arrived an hour ago.
There's no name on it
but it comes from Camden Town.
I was going to burn it.
I should have.
Well done, Tommy,
you've picked a side.
Now you're at war with Sabini.
Ada, are you coming for a drink?
No, the woman upstairs
is looking after Karl.
She goes mad if I'm late!
Ada Shelby?
No.
Your brother broke the rules.
I don't have a fucking brother.
Me and my friends here need
a bit of female company.
~ Let's go for a drive. ~ No!
~ Hold her steady, boys. ~ Get off!
Fucking hold him!
Tommy Shelby,
I missed you at my club.
I was at the races.
Sabini.
Don't say my name.
Jesus!
Franco,
take my name out of his mouth.
While you're in there,
do a bit of digging for gold.
Pay for the petrol.
You see how much I know about you?
I even know what's in
your fucking mouth.
Look at me.
Look at me!
You take up with the Jews.
Yeah, you think that's
what London's all about.
You can just come down,
pick a side.
You fucking clown!
Now your life is over.
My face is the last thing
you'll ever see on earth.
Your mistake.
You remember that
when you get to hell.
Finish him off.
I suppose we should
see if the bastard's still alive.
♪ On a gathering storm
comes a tall, handsome man
♪ In a dusty black coat
♪ With a red right hand. ♪