Translated By The Community Of WWW.MY-SUBS.COM
I just got served a black hand.
Everybody will have got one.
They're coming for us all.
These men will not leave our city
until our whole family is dead.
This was all my fault. It was me that shot
the old man. John's dead because of me.
Within a four-mile radius of the Garrison,
every man is a guard and a soldier for us.
We're going back, back to Small Heath.
That's how it works.
An eye for an eye.
It's called a vendetta.
We are an organization...
run different, I imagine.
None of you will survive.
And how is Tommy Shelby OBE going
to stop a revolution?
If I get Jessie Eden's trust,
she gives me the names of the instigators,
and I give them up to the Crown forces.
I want you to help my son achieve
his ambition.
You're a Peaky Blinder now, son.
We control him on the book, control
the odds.
We've got a lot going on though,
Tom.
That's why it'll be good to have
the kid around.
Mr Shelby will give you a 20% cut
if you put Goliath down in the
fourth round.
So you're going to take my boys, and you're
going to bring them to the ring as seconds?
Yeah, Tommy Shelby was right about
you, wasn't he?
Yeah, you're like me, Tommy.
You can't bear to watch a fight
which has got rules.
Tommy, imagine...
imagine that you could not see at
all,
you was born blind.
Then, one day,
you open up your eyes
and you can see everything in the
world...
..when before you could only touch
it or smell it.
There it is the revelation, innit?
I've had one.
Yeah, I saw a beautiful house down
in Margate.
A great big white building. Monkey
puzzle tree against the sky blue.
Beautiful. A piece of heaven,
actually.
You can see the way the Earth
curves, and I thought to myself,
Alfie, you know, what...what are you
doing? What are you doing?
Why don't you just sell every ounce
of gold
and sell every barrel of rum you got
and just buy yourself some time, mate?
I need to buy myself some time.
You're moving to Margate?
I am, actually, yeah.
I need to get myself some rest.
I need some rest.
Plus, the Americans are here now,
aren't they?
So, well, that's it, yeah.
It's been that way ever since
the war, innit, the Americans?
Big fucks small...
..always, actually.
There is a fight going on out there
between big and small.
Big will fuck small.
Right! Margate, then. Blue skies,
heaven.
I will see you, Tommy, by the pier.
Stay and watch the fight, Alfie.
No, you're all right. I already
know who wins, don't I?
Ta-ra!
Round one.
Fight, you bastard!
Bonnie... Bonnie.
Don't you touch it, Charlie.
I know he's a big bastard, but you
got to...
Where's Solomons?
Apparently he doesn't watch.
Look at that corner, look. The men
there, they don't know fighters.
I don't like it... You feel it
though, Tom, don't you?
I feel it. We're all right. We're
surrounded by soldiers, Arthur.
Alfie's men were strip-searched,
we're all right.
Right, come on, gypsy boy, let's
go.
So what did Tommy say when you
told him?
He said I'll get a weekly
allowance.
Oh, he can be romantic.
Of course, as company treasurer, I
shall be questioning that expense.
He said something like, "We've had
enough death, let's have some life."
Pol, this fight is fixed, isn't
it?
Well, gypsy boy's getting battered
out there.
Right, you said you had some news?
Lizzie has some news.
Polly!
Well, tell her. Now! While the men
are screaming for blood.
Have a swig, you're going to need
it.
I'm up the duff.
And it's Tommy's.
How far gone are you?
If I were going to London I'd be
in Coventry.
And are you carrying on past
Coventry?
All the way to fucking Piccadilly
Circus.
Have you found whether she's
having a boy or a girl, Pol?
No.
Go on, then.
It's a girl.
Call her Ruby. Ruby Shelby.
She'll be a star in a Hollywood
movie.
Congratulations.
Hello, Linda. Welcome to
extraordinary general meeting
of the Shelby ladies club.
Is there spit on my back?
There are men out there spitting -
it's fucking disgusting.
No. There's no spit on your back.
Don't let us stop you doing what you
came in to do.
What?
It's helping me get through the
fucking nightmare of being
stuck in the city.
Well, since you're here and you're
almost family,
Lizzie's got some news.
I'm pregnant.
Oh. And who's the father? Have you
managed to narrow it down?
Yes. It's Tommy.
Congratulations. You've won the
raffle at last.
Yeah, she's a real Shelby lady
now, Linda. Just like you.
Right, ladies, lets rejoin our
gentlemen.
And just remember, Linda, if they
spit, just spit back.
I'll see you out there.
All right.
Come on, Bonnie!
Right, you Brummie boys!
Forget your loyalty, boys!
You're still in control, Bonnie?
Yes.
Then take him.
It's not too late, boys.
I'll give you 2 to 1 on the big
Cockney, Goliath here.
Take it or leave it, boys.
Take it or leave it, boys. 2 to 1.
2 to 1 on the Cockney giant.
Look at them men in his corner,
look.
They don't know fighters.
They don't know the fucking ropes.
It's the pills and the booze
spooking you, Arthur.
Look at them. They don't stand
right, they don't move right.
They don't even care if he fucking
wins.
It's the fucking pills, brother,
all right?
Whoooo!
What the fuck are they laughing
about?
It's that new batch...too strong.
Come on, Bonnie!
Arthur, leave it!
Where's he going?
Sit down and watch the fight, eh?
Arthur! Come here!
Let me do my fucking job.
Bonnie! Bonnie! Are you OK?
I'll give you two to one now on
the Cockney!
Take it while you can.
Right...
Come on, Bonnie Boy! Bonnie, come
on. Get him!
Where are Tommy and Arthur?
I don't know.
Go on, Bonnie.
Go on, hit him!
Arthur?!
You fucking bastard!
I declare Bonnie Gold
the new welterweight champion of the
Midlands,
the south and the Home Counties.
Yes!
Tommy, what's happened?
Arthur's dead. He's dead.
Tommy, we have the other wop.
The cunt had a wire in his pocket.
Go on, Finn!
Go on, Finn.
Take his eyes, Finn. Do it for
Arthur.
Take his fucking eyes!
GROANING
Close the doors! No-one fucking
leaves!
My brother is dead.
Do you hear me?!
My brother is dead!
Tommy. Tommy.
Fuck off.
Tommy. Tom. Tom. Tommy.
Hello, Michael. There's been a
change of plan.
Mr Gold will come and get you.
Arthur's dead.
Tommy, I've been trying to think
of words.
Don't.
Words don't work.
Michael, we're in a grave situation.
Tommy has a plan.
Instead of going to Australia,
you're going to New York.
Why?
Because the company has business
to attend to in America.
Will I be coming back?
Your train leaves in an hour,
Michael.
You made a choice.
You knew I was going to be shot and
you chose not to tell me.
I chose my mum.
When all this business is over we'll
all be free to make our own choices.
So that's it?
You get the train to Liverpool
then the SS Monroe.
The boat sails tomorrow.
Now you can go.
I need an overseas connection,
please.
USA.
Tommy!
It's all right, let her come!
Please...until we're finished.
Your note talked about making
terms for peace.
But my son says there are no terms.
You took my husband and my son.
We took two of your brothers.
The vendetta is done.
We say the vendetta is won.
We will take everything you have.
All your businesses, signed over to
us.
You agree to this or my son will
kill you all.
One by one.
The vendetta is won. That's it.
No more killing.
Who did you think you were, Mr
Shelby?
Make sure he knows we're here to
buy his business!
Mr Solomons!
Mr Changretta is here to see you.
They say he was a captain.
Ah. I think you might want to tell
them not to open that fucking door.
It seems Mr Solomons has already
left town.
So all this is mine.
You don't knock?
You don't know my new address?
Hello, Lizzie, how are you?
I know your new address, Lizzie,
because it was me who bought you the
new fucking house.
Then why don't you visit it?
I've been busy.
Busy doing what?
Preparing for tomorrow.
Why? What's tomorrow?
Luca Changretta is coming to
Birmingham. It's our turn.
He's already taken over Alfie
Solomons, Sabini, the Titanics.
All of them.
And now he's coming to take
control of Shelby Company Limited.
What are we going to do about
that?
We're going to let him have it.
All that's left of the Peaky
fucking Blinders.
I've had my lawyer draw up these
papers.
They cover, er, every enterprise in
your possession.
Bars, restaurants, warehouses...
..every fucking thing that you've
taken all these years to gather
together.
You will sign them all over to my
family.
Or you're going to die, right here.
I would have buried you all.
But my mother, she, er, she knows
you.
She said it'll be worse for you
if I let you live...
..and take away everything that you
have.
Search 'em...
Especially don't trust this bitch.
So...
Sign.
Every fucking one of 'em.
You can sign them on your knees...
on the floor.
Get on your fucking knees and sign!
As a friend of mine once said...
..big fucks small.
So I had to find someone bigger than
you.
Now, you may know there are two
families in Brooklyn who want
to take over your monopoly on the
import of liquor into New York.
But if they moved against you in
New York they'll start
a war between the families.
But if you were to die in a
vendetta
with some fucking bookmaker in
Birmingham,
they could take over your business
without a war...
We also contacted a businessman in
Chicago.
He's also interested in moving into
the liquor business in New York.
His name is Alphonse Capone.
You been talking to that fat fuck?
See, all the blood relatives you
brought with
you from New York, they're all dead,
Mr Changretta.
And these men here, they work for
money, for the highest bidder.
They now have new orders.
Is that right?
Daniel?
Matteo?
Hey...
Very fucking...
Arthur's been injured but he's all
right, Pol.
We need to make them believe that
he's dead...
..to everyone but you, me and
Linda...
Arthur Shelby is dead.
I've got it all worked out.
We can use his death to win this
war.
Tell your people in Chicago that
Michael Gray will sign
the import licence to New York.
300 barrels of English Dry Gin a
month.
Leave! All of you.
Tell your boss what you saw here
today.
And tell him...
..you don't fuck with the Peaky
Blinders.
Right. Oi! Listen up.
Before we all go and eat, I'd like
to say a few words.
The last time we were all here, it
ended badly.
Yeah.
But now we're in a happier place.
That's it.
I'd just like to raise a toast...
Hold on.
A few words I'd like to say from the
heart,
and this time you're going to let me
finish, Tommy.
Now as you all know, Arthur Shelby
is dead.
Because of that, Tommy's offered me
a way out.
A new identity.
Start a whole new life for myself.
And I've thought about it.
Made a decision.
I ain't fucking going nowhere.
Our enemies are gone. Dead, all of
'em.
For the first time since me and my
two kid brothers...
Tommy and John...
..enlisted in the Warwickshire
Yeomanry, we have peace.
So, I think I'd like to make a
proposal.
All of you, the Shelby Company
Limited, insist that Tommy
here takes some time off.
It's time you took a holiday, Tom.
Put your feet up.
War is over. No-one wants to kill
us.
To peace.
I do hope you're going to leave
the dog out of this?
You were easy to find.
Yeah. There's a good reason for
that, Tommy.
I wanted it to be here.
I once told you, Alfie, for
business reasons or in bad blood,
I will kill you.
I have no business reasons. It seems
you have retired.
So this is all purely for bad
blood, is it, Tommy?
Yeah.
Right, yeah.
I told you I wanted it to be here.
Are you going to look after this
dog?
No.
Right, then. Well, his name is Cyril.
He'll be very upset and distressed,
so you'll need to find him someone.
You're not armed?
No! Don't be daft.
The only thing I've got on me...
is fucking cancer, mate.
Yeah.
Riddled with it.
Doctor told me
I might have picked it up in France
in a gas or something.
He even showed me a photograph of it, before I met you at the fight.
Alfie, stop talking.
So I said, Margate, right, and here I am. Come on, Tommy.
Alfie, look at me.
There's an honourable reason
now to pull that trigger.
Alfie, look at me.
So what you waiting for?
Just fucking get on with it, and
stop acting like a little girl.
Alfie!
Do you want me to do it for you?
Mr Shelby?
Mr Shelby, you are not yourself, I
should call a doctor.
It's all right, Frances.
I'll call Mrs Grey.
I know what this is.
It's just myself talking to myself
about myself.
Right... Thank you.
Charlie...
Since I know you
won't go yourself,
I've been to a doctor
on your behalf.
No, it's all right. None of
the boys know you're sick.
I'm not sick, Polly.
It starts when you stop.
When you rest.
Could be nerves, the war.
Might be the alcohol.
The blue devils, they call that.
Yeah, well. Yeah. Yeah,
it's the fucking booze.
It's the booze, the booze got hold
and the booze got in my bones.
Lizzie wants to see you.
No...
Tom, she's showing.
I don't want to see Lizzie, Pol.
Shit, maybe it's in us?
It's us Shelbys.
It's in our gypsy blood.
We live somewhere between life and
death.
Waiting to move on.
And in the end...we accept it.
We shake hands with the devils and
we walk past them.
Mr Shelby, you're meant to be
resting.
I have learnt something, Frances.
There is no rest for me in this
world.
Perhaps in the next.
Them there you pay out. This one
you have to think.
Use your fucking head, man. Right,
even money...
Whose fucking idea was it that I
go on holiday?
Welcome back, Tommy. How was it?
What did you get up to?
Went fishing. Played golf.
Golf's fucking boring.
Yeah, boring and easy.
Yeah, well, what's the plan?
I need you to give this to Jesse
Eden, by hand.
Yes, Mr Shelby.
By your hand. This will be the
last job you'll do for me.
Go to Glasgow and be with your
family. You're free.
You need to sign all of these.
So you shook hands with the devil?
Yeah, and I walked past him.
Pol.
I've had an idea.
Oh, fuck.
"Dear Jessie. Now more certainly
than ever
"I believe things must change.
"Things MUST change.
"The general strike is holding,
we've not an hour to lose.
"Meet me."
I've made up my mind, Jessie.
About what?
Your cause is now my cause. I want
to help.
The strike is holding.
I want to meet the people who can
take this further.
Are you serious?
Yeah, I've done a lot of thinking.
Right. I'll arrange a meeting.
The operator knows my voice. Give
me the name and the number.
His name is Casey Douglas.
Sparkhill 453.
Right.
And he's the leader of the cell?
He's in contact with London and
Moscow.
Good.
Yeah, Sparkhill 453.
You are quite a creature, Mr
Shelby.
When I received your note, I wasn't
sure you could deliver.
I have made contact with
the Soviet agent inside the
Birmingham Communist Party.
And you have a name?
And an address and a telephone
number.
I can be of great use to you.
I can give you the names of any
Communist Party member who is
prepared to cross the line into
armed revolution.
We are in the fourth day of a
general strike which appears
to be holding.
Even if it fails today...
tomorrow, they may succeed.
Mm.
And you're offering to help ensure
they never succeed.
If my cover is maintained...
..I can begin to shape the movement,
organise it myself...
And undermine it.
Rise through the ranks of the
wider socialist movement.
But, of course, you want something
in return. What this time?
A knighthood?
My proposal.
And my conditions.
For the attention of Winston
Churchill.
He holds me in very high regard.
Are you serious?
Breaking up a revolutionary cell
is one thing.
Given my position of influence in my
home city,
I can be of much more use to you
than that.
Ronald Carr, Conservative, 3,412
Bernard Hall, Liberal, 4,015.
Michael Ross, Communist, 6,406.
Thomas Shelby, Labour Party, 48,564.
I now declare Thomas Shelby to be
the new
Labour Member of Parliament for the
constituency of Birmingham South.