Hi, Frankie.
Hello.
Get in there.
Nothing like that first
drink of the day.
Go on, drink up. Enjoy.
Hey, what's he doing, huh?
Hey, they tell me you're
some dancer.
Well, how about a little
dance anyway?
No?
Come on!
Hey! Gimme back.
Don't horse around. What's
the big idea?!
Frankie!
Frankie, when'd you get back?
How are ya'?
You all right?
Y'know?
The monkey's gone.
Lemme look at ya.
Lemme look at ya!
Nah! Not even a posty-card!
You can't read, anyway.
Well, you could have drawed pictures?
Ah, YOU goofy punk.
How's the lost dog business?
Aach!
Soon as they see me hanging around,
people start lockin' up their mutts.
I tell ya, folks just don't have that trust
in their fellow man any more.
Y'know what I mean?
Hey, Antek?
- Look who's out.
- Frankie!
You all right?
- Clean?
- Yep.
Good kid.
Enough, already. Buy me a drink.
Sure.
Hey, look what the cat
dragged in.
Frankie, honey!
You were gone so long I thought
maybe you was made warden!
Hey, you're looking good, y'know?
Put on six pounds.
Wow! Six pounds.
He's gone so long I thought
maybe he's made warden.
How was it down there, Frankie?
Greatest place you ever see, Vangie.
She means Lexington.
I'm tellin' ya.
Ball games, great food.
I even learned how to play the drums.
You make it sound as if I missed something,
by not going to jail years ago.
It's a prison, no?
More a hospital, kinda.
Lemme show ya somethin'.
Ah, federal pens is always best.
Ask anybody.
Oh, I know.
He's gone so long, I think
he's made warden.
Ever see anything so pretty?
Don't touch!
Hey, how'd ya sneak 'em out, Frankie?
The guys give me 'em,
up there in the band.
They let you have a band?
Yeah, I was in it.
And they chipped in and bought
me these when I left.
Wow!
Long time, Dealer.
How was it there? Bad, huh?
It was all right.
Six months.
You can hardly wait, I bet.
Come over my place.
Come on.
No thanks, Louie.
You broke?
Now, ain't you being stupid.
It's for free!
I don't need it, is all.
I kicked it.
Oh!
Kicked it.
One of "them".
- I mean it.
- Sure!
I'll be around.
Frankie, don't do it.
Don't start up with that
peddler again.
Me?
I'd rather chop my arm off
before I let him touch it.
This Dr Lennox, that took care of me down
at the hospital - a real good guy.
He told me at least ten times, he said...
"Frankie, when you get out of here
you take even one fix..."
"...you're hooked again."
Don't worry about me, buddy boy.
Let's get outta here.
Thanks, Antek.
Antek - take care of this asset for me?
I got a customer comin' to get it.
Okay, Sparrow.
Aw, let him give you no gas.
Him? Huh.
I ain't gonna be around here long
enough to let him bother me.
I'm gonna get me a job in
a big-name band.
You're kiddin'.
What do you think I'm strengthenin'
my wrist for, buddy-o?
Guy teaches me drummin' down there
says that I'm a natural.
"Can't miss", he says.
"Arms made of pure gold".
You mean a job wanging
these drums?
I got everything planned, too.
Gonna call myself...
"Jack Duval".
Prolly I ain't gonna see you
around so much then, huh?
Ah, maybe I can set somethin'
up for you.
Carrying the instruments or somethin'.
Wow!!
Travellin' around the country.
High-type night clubs.
How's that sound to ya, punk?
When is it gonna be? When?
Right away. Today.
Hey, I'm the kinda guy... boy, when
I move - watch my smoke.
But I'm gonna need some
good clothes, though.
Ah, well. You go on up. I'm
gonna find you some.
Yeah. yeah. Size thirty-nine, get.
- Thirty nine.
- Stripes.
- Somethin' nice.
You stop that noise!
You and husband...
...or I throw you both out!
You hear?
I'll make all the noise I want.
Who is landlord? Me!
You do like I say!
Your mother's icebox, I
do like you say!
Frankie Machine!
Aw, ya look great!
How ya feelin', Frankie? Uh, I mean---
Fine, fine. Just fine.
- Hi, landlord.
- Mad!
She and husband, fight all the time.
Holler! Throw things!
Nothin' changes!
This is respectable house, and
I am respectable man.
Respectable, my eye. Go on and get out -
you're late for the parole board.
Frankie?
Oh, Frankie!
You're home!
Oh!
Oh, Frankie. I love you so much.
Oh, Frankie - I've missed you so.
You don't know how much
I've missed you.
I've been so lonely Frankie,
without you.
Sshh!
So lonely. Lonely.
Zosch. Don't cry, Zosch.
Lemme look at you.
My eyes are going to be all red.
Nah. You look fine, Zosch.
Honest?
Has the cold sore gone?
Ah, ya look real good.
I had this cold sore.
I wanted to look real nice for you,
when you came back.
I was afraid it wouldn't be gone...
...so I put this goofy salve
on it to dry it.
Oh, Frankie.
Oh, Zosch.
Everything's gonna be all right.
Oh, you didn't see. Look!
Vi got the cake by the bakery.
But the sign, I made.
It's sorta like for a
welcome home.
Gee, it's like a real party
or somethin'.
Real nice, Zosch.
How are you, Frankie?
- I'm clean.
- Sure?
I kicked it, for keeps.
Did it hurt?
How was it there for you?
Oh, they treated me fine,
down there.
There was this doctor - this Dr Lennox.
He was real good to me.
Frankie.
Did you miss me?
Of course I missed you, Zosch.
What kind of silly question is that?
Of course I missed you.
Honest, no kiddin'.
- What you got there?
- You'll see.
Oh - I brought you somethin'.
Oh... oh, it's an exquisite thing.
You like it? I made it myself.
Out of cigarette wrappers.
Oh, it's just an exquisite thing, is all.
- You made it?
- Yeah.
For a hobby, like.
See, part of the cure...
...is to keep yourself busy, doin'
things you enjoy.
Like for instance I wanted to learn
to drum, and music.
And Dr Lennox got 'em
to help me do it.
During the day I was kept busy enough,
but sometimes at night...
...I'd get restless and I'd want to keep
my mind off the craving.
I made that.
There's something important
I gotta tell you.
What?
I forget right now.
A whistle?
Oh. I was scared sometimes,
being alone.
So Vi got it for me, I should blow for
her when I wanted her.
Go on - you were telling me.
Oh, well.
The first thing you do when you get there, you
talk to a doctor for about two hours---
Wild! I know what it is. I know
what I had to tell ya.
Vi took me to this movie...
...and the girl's kid brother
had a friend in it.
Now who do you think he looked like?
- Who?
- You!
That was a good movie.
Stage show was real good, too.
We owe Vi eighty cents for
the movie, I was broke.
And we owe her for the cake, too.
How come you didn't have any money?
Schwiefka didn't kick in regular?
No.
Well, he was supposed to!
It was his joint they raided, not
mine. I was just a dealer.
I kept my mouth shut and
took the rap!
If he didn't send fifty a month
regular, how much did he?
Well, he sent fifty, but
not regular.
You see, Vi had to kick in
for me, sometimes.
She took good care of ya?
Did you have fun with her?
Yeah.
But not like, when you're here.
It was terrible being
alone, Frankie.
And my legs, when they hurt...
...she don't massage like you,
when they hurt.
What did they say by the
clinic, Zosch?
I stopped going by that
goofy clinic.
The clinic must know what's
right, Zosch.
You gotta start the clinic again.
You gotta get well.
Vi dreamed that this new doctor round
the corner, he cured me.
I'd have gone to him already, but
he ain't free like the clinic.
But now you're back, makin' money
again by Schwiefka, I'll go.
I've finished with Schwiefka.
I don't deal for him no more.
But you always deal!
You're a dealer. You're the best
dealer in the business.
No more. I'm a drummer now.
Don't make jokes, Frankie.
I never know when you're
making jokes.
Who's jokin', Zosch? Listen.
Nice, huh?
This Dr Lennox, I told him
my whole life story.
From when I was born, almost.
And about you and me.
But he told me that if I lived
when I got out...
...like I lived before I went in there...
...chances are I would be hooked
again in no time.
So that's why I want to
get with a band.
Listen.
How's that?
Cute.
What you tell him about
me, this doctor?
I told him about...
...gettin' some money and
gettin' you well.
And he said gettin' with a band
was a good way to go at it.
He even gave me the name of a guy
in town, right here, to get a job.
That's nice.
I mean if this man with a job ever
heard of this great doctor.
Most times these things just
don't come through.
I got this.
- What is it?
- It's a letter from the doc.
I think I'll go call him now.
Now? Let's talk about it tomorrow.
I'll be right up, Zosch.
You ain't even tasted
the cake!
But I'll only be a minute.
I'll be right up.
No, now, Frankie!
First...
...taste a piece of nice...
.“cake.
Hey, ya comin', baby?
Yeah, yeah. I'm comin', Johnny.
- Hey, Molly.
- Yeah, I'm comin', Johnny.
I want to talk to Mr Harry Lane, please.
- How 'bout it, huh?
- Machine.
Frankie Machine.
Yeah, I got a letter of
introduction for him.
From Dr Lennox.
Yeah.
Hello, Frankie.
Dr Martin Lennox.
How ya been, Molly?
All right.
Come on, baby, let's go.
- Yeah - I'm comin', Johnny.
- Yeah.
A guy I met, when you was away.
Mr Lane?
I got a letter for ya, yeah.
Come on, what d'ya say, kitten?
This afternoon, huh?
Would you? I sure do appreciate
it, Mr Lane.
Thank you so much.
Okay. Goodbye.
Frankie!
A new thing by Brach's
Department Store.
No sales girls!
It's just help yourself.
It's what they call a
"honour system".
What'sa matter, Frankie?
Feel that material!
An' I figured...
...as long as I'm there ---
Nice, huh?
You all right?
Frankie?
I got the drumming job.
Already? Wow!
When I move, I move like
a streak, punk.
Think it looks all right, Zosch?
How come ya ask me,
all of a sudden?
I just wanna know if it looks
all right, Zosch.
And my name ain't Zosch.
It's Sophia.
What's the matter?
Nothing's the matter.
'Cept how would you feel, if
your spine was hurtin'?
Well, why didn't you say so?
On account it's your first
day back, I...
...I just didn't want you
should worry.
Don't be like that, Zosch.
Is it bad?
Well, maybe the new doctor'd do
me some good, huh?
We'll go see him when
I get back.
Take me now, Frankie.
Zosch, you--- I got this appointment. You
know how much it means to me.
We'll go as soon as I get back.
Please.
- Frankie!
- I'll hurry. I'll hurry.
Frankie! Well---
Gimme a little more massage
then first, huh?
Zosch.
I'm doin' this for you. To get some money,
so you can get a good doctor.
Aw, please Frankie?
Look, I'll get ya a dog, too.
How's that, huh?
Get her a dog, will ya?
I'll give the matter my
personal attention.
Just have confidence in
the management.
Wish me luck, Zosch?
Oh...
Frankie!
Oh, Frankie?
Wait!
Wait, Frankie!
Can't be two places at once.
What could I do?
Yeah, she just don't realise.
Aw, shut up, punk!
"Just don't realise."
How would you like to
be nailed to a chair?
Frankie, Frankie. How are ya?
Antek!
Well, it didn't do you no harm.
Did it, Frankie?
Ooh, you look good.
That's right, Schwiefka, it was
a real country club.
Hmm.
They give you this when
they let you out?
Give him nothin'. I bought
it by Brach's.
You know, I come as soon
as I hear you're out.
I figured he's worried about
getting his job again.
Tell him "don't worry".
Schwiefka don't forget so quick.
Job's waitin'.
You need a dealer, you say'?
Need? No!
I been dealin' myself, and man, I built
up a game like nobody's business.
I got a great followin'.
The play is bigger than ever.
I hear you wasn't doin' so good.
From who?
When I say "great", I don't
mean a lot.
A few, but loaded.
So, what do you want me for?
Like I'm tellin' ya...
...I take care of my friends.
Can I polish your halo, Schwiefka?
Only a quarter!
Knock it off, punk.
Look.
I've been doin' all right...
but I don't say that the customers like
me better than they like you.
The dealer makes the house.
I know that.
Whaddaya Say?
No.
Ya dealin' for some other joint?
I ain't dealin' for nobody.
I ain't dealin' for nobody, no more.
Is that the way ya repay me?
Didn't I send money to Zosch?
Eh, I've gone and told all my friends that you're
gonna be workin' for me again.
What am I supposed to do?
Far as I'm concerned you can go back
to matchin' pennies with school kids.
Why, you---
Hey, Antek!
Antek!
Who is he?
Drunky?
His name's Johnny somethin'.
He's house-man for Gubachek's
Pool Room.
Is that a thing with him?
They see each other.
You wanna meet him?
Naw.
So long, Antek.
See ya, Frankie.
Hey, you!
Get in, Dealer.
Who, me? What for?
You too, punk.
I didn't do nothin'.
Now, wait a minute, Kvorka. Listen!
I'm on my way to get a job.
It's important to me!
Get.
You can pick me up
some other time!
I just need an hour! Be a
good guy, will ya?
Shut up. Get in.
What are you talking, Kvorka? You looking
to get sued for libel or somethin'?
I could sue you right now.
You're lookin' good, Dealer.
Real good.
When they let ya out?
Monday, they let me out.
What's the charge, Kvorka?
Shoplifting from Brach's.
This suit.
Who told ya a thing like that?
Little bird.
Little bird with a cigar.
Schwiefka!
That all ya could stay
outta trouble?
Two days?
Dealer, Dealer.
Listen, Bednar. I got a chance for
a job playin' with a band.
Honest! If you don't believe me call the
guy on the phone. He'll tell ya.
Well, just give me a half hour. Please?
Sure, you can wear my badge too.
Book him, and hold the suit.
Look, all I need's a half hour.
Gimme a break, will ya?
I don't make the rules, Dealer.
Now, listen. I tell ya, ya can't hold me...
...I'm unencapable.
I ain't smart enough to be
runnin' around loose.
And I'm too goofy to
be locked up.
The neck! Will ya let go
of the neck?
- I got a complaint to make.
- Let go of the neck!
Hey you! I'm talkin' to you.
Oh, the old silent treatment, huh?
All right. Let's have ya number, fella.
I'll show ya, ya can't give
me the business.
Your goose is cooked, copper!
Oh, God...
Frankie, ya got a cigarette?
Do a cigarette trick.
You know, just to break
the daily monotony.
Wow!
Psst!
Dealer.
Hello, Dealer.
I come runnin' as soon
as I heard.
Ya want I should get
ya out, Dealer?
You fink!
The store will drop the charges.
But thirty-seven bucks' a
lot of dough.
How'd I know ya'd pay me back?
You fink!
Be different if you was
dealin' for me.
If you wanna deal for me,
I can get ya out.
Dirty, lousy stool pigeon!
I don't know what ya mean.
Just tryin' to do ya a favour.
Yes or no?!
Okay.
Took off like a whipped dog.
He's scared of you, Frankie.
Nobody's ever been scared of me.
Them Krauts was scared of you.
You was a big man in the army.
Big man.
I was the guy that picked the fly
spots outta the black pepper.
Get me out!
Get me out! I can't take it!
Can't stand it! Get me out!
Get me out!
Out! Get me out!
I wanna fix! I wanna fix!
I wanna fix!
Can you gimme a fix?
Can ya? Can ya gimme a fix?
Can ya gimme a fix?
I wanna fix!
I wanna fix! Gimme a fix!
Gimme a fix! I wanna fix!
Aw, gimme a fix, go on!
Jack's check, bullets say a buck.
Big AC's. Here we go down and dirty.
Better luck next time, friend.
Man with a hammer
bumps a buck.
Jack calls.
Bucket of paint, all red.
Coffee!
Doesn't mean a thing, if ya
haven't got the King.
A winner every hand. You bet
more, you get more.
Slip me half, make me laugh.
You still take tips, Dealer?
Or don't they pay so good
in the music game?
What happened to that big
job you had lined up?
You stink out the joint?
Give us a fresh deck.
I decide when we need a
fresh deck at this table.
Hey, Louie...
...borrow me a dirty dollar?
Get back on the door,
lame brain.
I take orders only from Frankie.
Don't give me lip, ya cheap
little hustler.
Hustler, schmustler. I'm legit
compared to some.
Ain't no fourteen-year-old junkies
waitin' around to see me!
Do you wanna die?
And here we go, down and dirty.
Hey!
I'll deal the next one down.
Sorry.
What's it a sign of, when a dealer's
hands begin to shake?
Schwiefka, take the slot
for a while, will ya?
All right, then, new deal.
Okay, then, here we go,
down and dirty.
Ah, Ace. Seven.
You know what's eatin' at ya?
You shot off the mouth about
kickin' it for keeps.
So now you're ashamed
of even thinkin'...
...well, what you're thinkin'.
Ain't that right?
You know I don't talk about my customers,
so who'd be the wiser?
Why fight it, Dealer? For
who? For what?
Come over my place.
Whaddya say?
Huh?
I'll be around.
They told me you was
workin' here an' I...
...was passin' by an' I thought I'd
come in an' have a drink.
Oh, I've been here a while.
Doin' any good?
All right.
Small cut on the game, usual
cut on the drinks.
Ain't got all night, Jack.
Right.
Have something.
- Rye.
- Two doubles.
You didn't have to do
that, Frankie.
No reason you should go losin' money
by wastin' your time talkin' to me.
You know you're no waste.
I've been hopin' you'd come see me.
You know how it is, Molly.
Sure...
...so busy, and all.
Well, here's to it, Molly-o.
"Molly-o".
I ain't heard that since
you went away.
You're lookin' good, Frankie.
Feelgood.
They tell me you're gonna be
a drummer now.
Yeah!
I got an appointment with
a man tomorrow.
Oh, that's swell.
Ah, probably I won't get
the job, though.
Sure ya will.
Probably I don't play good enough.
I bet ya play fine.
You was always whistlin', drummin'
on tables and things.
Real good, too.
- Aach!
- No, I mean it.
You've got a natural rhythm.
I was thinkin', maybe I'd
take a stage name.
"Jack Duval".
Jack Duval.
Yeah, that's real class.
It is, ain't it.
That's a swell name.
Just fits ya, Frank.
This guy I'm gonna see tomorrow,
he books all the big bands.
If I get in with him, boy,
I'll wear a tux.
You'll look swell in a tux.
I already got the drums.
I---
I need a buck.
Ante-up kid, huh?
I got lonely.
I needed somebody, and he's a...
...poor, beat guy who needs
somebody too.
Everybody needs somebody.
But you can do better than him.
Can I, Frankie?
Molly, I...
...I thought a lot about you,
while I was away.
About you and me and Zosch.
How it'd never work out between
you and me as long as...
...she was upstairs sitting
in that chair.
It'd be different if she didn't love me
an', she wasn't so helpless.
You can't make a fool of somebody who
loves ya, an'--- an' they're so helpless.
That's why I didn't come
around sooner.
And that's why I ain't comin'
around no more.
You understand?
Sure... sure, I understand.
You're a good girl, Molly.
Sure. Real good.
Frankie?
Good luck with that
fella tomorrow.
You're not the first to come to me
with a letter from Dr Lennox.
I've taken care of a lot
of you people.
The Doc, he told me.
I like doin' it, understand...
so don't feel that this is charity
or anything like that.
Now, um...
...have you played professionally before?
Only down at Lexington.
I see. Well, then you wouldn't
mind auditioning?
I mean, I know some band leaders
who might have an opening...
...but they'd have to be sure
that you could play.
- Oh, sure, sure.
- All right, then.
There's only one thing, Frankie.
You see...
...a good many people like yourself...
...well, they mean well, but they're...
...well, they're weak. They let me down.
I mean...
...I go to all this trouble. Vouch for them...
...and they go back on the habit.
It makes me look bad.
Oh, I wouldn't. Honest.
All right, I'm telling you this because...
...well, once a man lets me down,
I'm done with him.
He comes back on his knees.
And don't think that some
of them haven't.
I wouldn't let you down, Mr Lane.
Good.
I'll call you, er... let me see, urn...
...a week from Friday. About noon.
- All right?
- Fine.
I sure do appreciate it.
Aw, forget it.
- Bye.
- Goodbye.
You like my hair better this way -
or upswept, Frankie?
Huh?
Well, you can at least tell me? it
ain't my fault he don't phone.
What did I say?
"Just don't hold your breath 'till you hear
from that guy." That's what I said.
He told you noon, and here it is
almost six o'clock already...
...so how can you still
think he'll phone?
Honest, I'm surprised at ya!
Why... I just don't want ya should
eat your heart out, is all.
Forget the whole thing, Frankie.
I bet he has.
Do you think he's got nothing better
to do than worry about you?
Do you think he don't sleep nights,
on account of Frankie Machine?
- Bet he don't get no---
- Ha!
Excuse me, erm...
Hello?
Oh. Just a minute.
It's for you.
Hello...?
Are you Dr. Dominovski?
Yes, I came as soon as I could.
Oh.
Well, how ya feelin', little lady?
See? The doc asks "how am I feelin'."
Ah, we'll have you feelin' fine
in one, two, thu-ree.
What is this?
It happens, friend, to be an Electric Blood
Reverser and Spine Manipulator.
It helps to reverse the blood.
- What's the gimmick?
- Gimmick?
It happens so, brother, that...
...I am a member of the American
Association of Medical Hydrology...
...Psychology and Divine Healing.
Where's the socket?
Mmm, cold hands.
Poor circulation.
Eat lots of hot things.
Chilli, peppers, hot sauces.
Pickles?
Er, not more than three a day.
Now, lean forward.
And we'll vibrate the vertebraes.
Do you know how I got like I am?
My spine was hurt.
Oh, I can see that.
The little fibres in the vertebrae
is locked together.
In a car accident, it was hurt.
Three years ago, May 11th.
Maybe you've read about it
in the papers, huh?
This is the car it happened in.
That's me, laying there.
My husband was the one driving
the car, and he was drunk.
Drunk, eh?
He got me in this accident, and smashed
me up good so's I can't...
...walk no more or dance no
more or nothin'.
An' he married me right here...
- ...in the hospital chapel.
- Zosch!
Feelin' a little better?
Uh-huh.
Much better.
Help yourself.
Hey, Frankie - guess what?
I got that dog for Zosch.
Drinks beer and every claw and
hair of him's a champeen.
- Champeen of what?
- Retrievin'!
He brings back empties.
Here, I show ya. Come
on, Beauty. Here.
Get it, Beauty.
He's all dog.
Ya can make money outta
him, Frankie.
See, what he's good at...
...is catching them squirrels in the park, and
shaking their dirty peanuts outta 'm.
Y'know what I mean?
Only thing - he's trained to chase
only one kinda squirrel.
And they're gettin' kinda rare in Chicago,
on account of the climate's changin'.
Y'know what I mean?
So he's just hanging around, waitin' for
the climate to change back a little.
He's got a real fightin' heart.
He's dizzy, but he's still in there tryin'.
- Take the dog up to Zosch.
- Frankie!
Can I go with ya?
No.
In a minute, Dealer.
Five bucks.
Last time it was two.
That was more than six months ago.
Before you went away.
They keep raising the price on me.
They keep doin' that? Hm.
I'll have to find somethin'
to take its place.
Monkey's never dead, Dealer.
The monkey never dies.
When ya kick him off...
...he just hides in a corner,
waitin' his turn.
The monkey'll die waitin'.
He ain't climbin' up on
my back no more.
Never again.
I mean it.
Sure.
Look, Frankie!
Look how he drinks it.
Oh, he's so cute!
- He's gotta thirst like a barfly!
- Shh, shh, shh.
Hallo?
You still expectin' that
connection to call?
For your own peace of
mind, forget him.
The Doc said I could count on Mr Lane,
and the Doc doesn't lie.
The Doc!
Look at me. A doc told you I'd be up
and around in no time. An' am I?
Have you seen my sticks?
Seen my drumsticks anywhere?
You know what I'm going to
get for this little dog?
A little raincoat, like for when it rains.
Plaid, maybe.
Or maybe all yeller, huh?
Where are my drumsticks, Zosch?
How'd they get up here?
Ya liked that, didn't ya? Hm?
Zosch, I never keep 'em way up here.
Drank it all up, didn't ya. Huh?
Zosch!
I put 'em there.
I stood right up. I walked right over
and I put 'em there. All right?
No kiddin'. How did---
Maybe Vi, when she was straightenin'
up for me. I don't know.
Stop pickin' on me!
Frankie.
Ya can't keep stonin' yourself about it.
There must be a million drummers play
better'n you do can't get jobs.
Just remember that, an' you're
gonna feel better.
Yeah, sure I will.
Yeah.
Can the noise!
What's this for, Zosch?
What?
Oh! Vi.
She laid out for groceries.
We owe her even more.
You got any?
No.
I don't know what we're doin'
with all our money.
Don't ya get enough cards
by Schwiefka?
I just do it to kill the past
time, that's all.
What about my past time?
What'd you say this is for?
Sit here all the time, you
don't even talk to me.
Have we got any more beer?
I'd like some.
Beer bloats, Zosch, when
ya can't exercise.
Here, pick a card.
Everythin's no good for me.
I, I'm only twenty-five and it's like
I'm an old lady already.
Is it my fault I can't exercise?
You wanna pick a card or don't
ya wanna pick a card?
No, I don't wanna pick a card!
All I want is... just a little---
Little what, Zosch?
Oh, just a little---
A little beer, a little fun -
a little anything!
I can't dance no more. I can't swim.
And now I can't even drink beer!
I don't even know what kinds
they got any more.
What other kinds they got
these days, Frankie?
All right! Pretend like I ain't here.
It's what you're all the time wishin' anyway.
That I got killed that night.
I don't wish any such thing!
If I don't talk, you get mad. If I say
anything, you bite my head off.
I don't know whether I'm comin'
or goin' anymore, Zosch.
I told ya. It gives me headaches.
Well, I gotta practise sometime, Zosch.
The job comes along, I wanna be ready.
Job? The job!
Take 'em down to ya girlfriend
if ya gotta practise.
What?
Take them down and give
her the headache.
Do ya know what ya sayin', Zosch?
Ya know what ya talkin' about?
Don't give me that innocent look.
I ain't said two words to her
since I come back.
Just cause I sit here, you think
I don't know what goes on?
Not two words.
I know plenty.
Cut it out, will ya, Zosch?
Cut it out.
Take 'em down to that tramp if
you wanna make noise.
Go on, take 'em down to her,
why don't ya?
All right. I Will.
Frankie!
Frankie, I didn't mean---
"it's a long drive to right field."
"it's going, going, it's gone!"
"it's a home run!"
I got twelve cents toward a beer - if
I had fifteen, I'd be all right.
- I got, urn, six cents here. Here ya are.
- Thanks.
I ain't gonna stand it much longer.
The heartaches my old man gives me.
You know what he likes to do most?
Tear the dates off the calendar.
Watchin' 'im.
That's supposed to be my big
Saturday night pleasure.
Sometimes he loses all control and tears
off a whole week's at once.
Bleatin' like a billy goat.
You know what would fill up that
empty spot in your life?
- Yeah?
- A dawg.
Ask a satisfied customer.
Frankie, that, that, that dawg I got ya...
...makes a big difference in
ya life, don't it?
Yeah, big.
"Dobbs to second."
I wanna see you.
I wanna see you!
After the innin'!
I'll still bet ya six to five.
"---pitch. And it's a strike. Strike one."
"London's getting set again."
"There's the pitch - London swings.
And it's a high foul."
"Loveridge is trying to get it. "
"it may go into the stands."
"He's, he's going to try. It's
going to be close."
"Roberts makes a tremendous leap and---"
How are you, Frankie?
You make out all right with
the fella with the job'?
What, the drumming job?
Yeah, fine, fine.
Well... not so fine.
He sorta tapped out on me.
He promised to call me but---
It's too bad.
A million drummers in the
world, how do I rate?
Maybe he lost your number?
- Aach!
- It happens.
Maybe he's just wishin' you'd...
...you'd get in touch.
He'd think I was a pest.
Should he?
Good drummer, that's somethin'
that don't turn up every day.
Go on, Frankie. Call him.
Call him, Frankie.
Come on, Molly. Watch
the game, huh?
Oh. I don't feel like it, Johnny.
Why don't you go ahead?
I'll wait for you.
Yeah, Studio B. Monday morning.
Fine. Thank you, Mr Lane.
Bye.
Monday! I got an audition
Monday. Me!
Yeah. He told me to join the union,
and be ready to work.
Oh, that's swell, Frankie.
You know, he did lose
my phone number.
He was trying to find
me all week long.
Here I was, ready to forget
the whole thing.
Gee, if you hadn't opened your mouth
I wouldn't have called him.
Oh, sure you would.
I got an audition with a big band.
Me, on TV.
Practise a lot, Frank.
Practise, I'll beat those
heads to a shred.
Only, I gotta find a place where.
Zosch can't stand the noise.
Molly?
D'you suppose, maybe, I could
put the drums in...
...your place, an'...
...sorta drop in, once in a while?
Why not?
Molly, why not?
Oh... Johnny wouldn't understand.
So what could he do?
It ain't a question of what
he could do, Frankie.
Fella like Johnny can't do
much about anything.
It's a question of what
it does to him.
I'm all he has in the world.
Don't want to hurt him.
Molly - for cryin' out loud!
Oh, you don't know, Frankie.
A fella like him...
...sometimes, when we're alone---
What does he do? Cry?
He's a lush, Molly.
He's a hundred-percent,
habitual drunk.
Look, everybody's a habitual somethin'.
With him it's liquor, is all.
Please, Molly? Molly-0?
It ain't just that, Frankie.
I don't want us to start with
each other again.
Look, what you said about
us not being good...
...it was the truth.
Even before you went away, I...
...I tried to---
It just doesn't add up.
It never did. It never can.
Well, give it a chance. I told
you it would, one day.
All my life has been "one day".
On and on and on.
I got drums. I'm headed
for a good job.
Is that so "on and on and on"?
I'll make some money.
Make Zosch well.
What's so "on and on and
on" about that?
Don't shut me out, Molly.
I'm tryin'.
You wanted to see me?
No!
What do ya mean "no"?
Vi?
Here.
What we owe.
Frankie, Vi says "Can she trust me?"
Tell her, tell her, Frankie, what
a honest hustler I am.
Frankie.
I guess, maybe, you could
drop in once in a while.
Thanks, Molly-o.
See you tonight.
How's that?
Real nice.
Shoulda heard what I did with
Perdido a little while ago.
Good, huh?
I hope the neighbours liked it, too.
I'm very big with the neighbours.
They keep bangin' on the pipes...
...to let me know how much
they appreciate it.
I won't let it go to my head, though.
You keep playing drums...
...at five a.m. and you'll see
what goes to your head.
You slip me a smile, and I'll
give you my autograph.
You won't have to fight your way through
the bobby-soxers to get to me.
I'll bet those bobby-soxers
go for ya, at that.
Aach!
You tired?
But in a very nice way.
I've been feelin' good all night.
I joined a musicians union today.
Schwiefka loan ya the money?
Him? Huh.
Who did?
Nobody.
I'm gonna hock the drums.
Oh, Frankie, no!
I got it figured out pretty good.
When I get a job, I'll take an advance,
and get the drums out again.
Meantime, I'll use a practice pad.
Ya shoulda' asked Schwiefka.
Haven't even seen him.
You didn't go to work?
I've been practisin' here all night.
I quit the game, Molly.
It wouldn't have hurt ya to wait
a coupla days, Frank.
I wanted to quit.
I'm quittin' a couple of things.
Is it bad?
Not too bad.
You shouldn'a started again.
Who knows why I started
in the first place.
I guess, in the beginning you
do it only for kicks.
Louie gave me my first
shot for nothin'.
I thought I could take it,
or leave it alone.
So I took it.
And I took it again and again.
And one day, Louie wasn't around.
I nearly went crazy,
till I found him.
Oh, I was sick.
I was so sick.
You can't be that
sick and live.
That's when I knew
I was hooked.
There was a forty-pound
monkey on my back.
The only way to get along with a load
like that, is to keep leanin' on a fix.
Don't.
I'm one of the lucky ones, Molly.
I kicked it, and I'm not too far
hooked to kick it again.
I've had my last fix.
I mean it, Molly.
Tell me somethin'.
You think those bobby-soxers
will really go for me?
You're goin' to be such a ham.
Yeah, maybe I'll get Sparrow
a job with the orchestra.
Or when I can put enough money together
I can get Zosch into a...
...real good hospital.
So she can walk and dance again.
And then, maybe---
- Who is it?
- Schwiefka. Open up.
Just a minute.
- All right, all right. Where is he?
- Good morning, Mrs Machine.
- Frankie?
- Frankie! Where is he?
What is it? What'd he do?
What'd he do? You
know what he did.
He quit!
No notice. No nuthin'.
He sends word by that misfit
that he's through.
I had to take the spot myself.
- Where is he?!
- Aah!
Oh!
He wasn't at the game?
Would we be lookin' for him all over
if he was at the game?
He eats my bread. Six years
he eats my bread.
He gets put away, I send
ya money regular.
He gets out, I give him
his job back, I---
Shut up.
- What do you mean "shut up"?
- Shut up!
You think it was easy talkin' fellas
like Williams and Marquette...
...up to a two-bit game like yours?
- Louie, Louie, I---
- I sold 'em on Frankie.
Why we gettin' excited?
They... they're fat in the pocket
and hungry for action.
We finally get a chance
to score big...
...and you lose the Dealer.
Look, Louie, I swear...
...I swear, when Marquette and Williams
come the Dealer will be there.
Or a player just as good.
There ain't none as good.
Why didn't you offer him more money?
A piece of the play, even?
From your end or mine?
What's the difference whose end?!
You expect me to stand here and
argue about pennies?
Your end!
Look“.
I'm a musician.
Well, how does it feel?
Well, it feels like...
...you better hang onto my arm
or I go up like a balloon.
I'm a musician.
Where're we goin'?
I dunno. But I wanna
buy you something.
Ah, no.
I gotta spend some
money or I'll bust.
How about one of those in green?
Oh, Frankie.
Maybe a colour TV set?
They're pretty-
Go on.
Will ya look at this production?
And only for cookin'.
Now who would wanna
thing like that?
Boy...
...it's goofy, huh?
It's pretty, huh?
I wonder what he does
for a livin'?
Him?
Well, he must make a nice dollar.
Look the way he dresses her.
Kitchen like that.
I notice he don't help her
none, though.
I bet he never even married the girl.
Look at that - she ain't even
wearing a ring on her finger.
She takes it off when
she cooks, maybe?
And he's tired after a
hard day's work.
All right, so let him sit there...
...but at least he could talk
to her once in a while.
Doesn't have to sit there with his
nose buried in a magazine.
I would talk to her.
What would you say?
Oh, I'd say "how ya been?"...
..."how did it go today?"...
..."what's for supper?".
Steak. Steak's for supper.
And everything went fine today.
Steak? Good.
Now, how about you and
me steppin' out...
...tonight, after we eat?
Why don't we just stay home?
Turn on some music.
Yeah.
I like that better.
We'll just stay home and
turn on some music.
I wish it was Monday, already.
Hi Zosch.
Oh! Where ya been?
Schwiefka was here - said you quit him.
Where you been?
Look.
Why'd you quit him?
I got a tryout on Monday.
And if the bandleader likes the
way I play - I'm hired.
Frankie...
Go tell Schwiefka you was foolin'.
You'll deal.
Maybe this bandleader won't
like how you play?
Zosch! Look - I joined the Musician's Union.
Why you gotta go around
changin' things?
Why can't it be like always?
Why you gotta quit dealin', Frankie?
How we gonna live with
no money comin' in?
It'll start comin' in - Monday.
But, suppose they call this
great tryout off?
You can't tell me it's a
sure thing, can you?
Oh, Frankie.
Deal for Schwiefka, like always?
Forget this "great job"!
I quit dealing, Zosch.
I can't take the chance, don't
you understand?
If the joint gets raided and
I get picked up again...
...Mr Lane would be through with me.
And then how would I
play with a band?
How you gonna play if Schwiefka
gets ya arms broke?
Goon
Yeah - right here, he said it.
And he wanted to slap
me around, too.
WHY CAN'T IT BE LIKE ALWAYS?!
Antek.
You miserable piece of humanity.
I got a right to quit if I want.
Marquette and Williams are comin' tomorrow.
Don't you realise the significance?
Leave me alone.
I'll leave ya alone.
In the alley with the cats lookin'.
That's enough, Schwiefka.
You don't wanna deal, you
don't wanna deal.
What're you talkin' about
all of a sudden?
Don't raise your voice
to me, you slob.
He's no slave. You can't force him.
So what's the use?
He, er---
You had the best of him all these
years. Don't be a pig!
Ain't interested. Right?
All right, all right.
Marquette and Williams, never heard of 'em.
Money? Huh! Somethin' to blow ya nose on.
I wash my hands.
He's just a pig, is all.
Still, you can't blame him so much.
Lettin' the big ones get away, on
account of the best dealer...
...in the business ain't workin'
for ya no more.
That ain't easy to swallow.
You're the best, all right.
The old squeeze play. Huh, Louie?
Been tried on you before, huh?
Naw, I'm new around here.
Are we really askin' so much,
Dealer? One night!
I like---
You help us make a bundle. We'll spread a little
of that ol' sunshine around.
Couldn't you use a couple of hundred?
Maybe...
...two-five-oh?
Huh?
Two-five-oh pays a lot of
doctor bills, Dealer.
Tomorrow, huh?
- Frankie, I---
- Let him make up his mind.
Okay.
But for one night!
Win or lose, sun-up I case the deck.
Sure, you're the dealer.
What a load off! Now I can sleep.
Take care of that arm.
The character, huh?
Were you jackin' up the price just now,
or do you really have this music job?
If they like what they hear.
Chance-y, huh'?
Nervous?
So what are we waitin' for?
Don't talk about it. It's tough enough!
I know, I know.
I put down a cravin' once.
No.
Candy - sweets.
I used to be eatin' it all the time.
Got examined for the army. They said
"You got sugar in your blood, friend."
"You gotta give up sweets forever,
or it's 'goodbye Charlie'."
I had to give up candy.
My gums bleed for ya!
It's awful.
It was.
That unfinished feelin'
you got all the time.
- Well, I don't have to tell you.
- So don't!
I mean, you got this one thing
on the mind, all the time.
Can't stop thinkin' about it.
You're just a mine of
information, ain't ya?
You know what I did?
I said to myself...
"Okay - off sweets, forever."
Well... "forever" can start tomorrow.
For once in my life...
...I'm gonna eat all the candy
that I can hold.
I bought eighteen dollars and twenty three cents'
worth of candy, lugged it up to my room.
All night long, I ate candy.
I was sick.
I was sweatin'.
But I kept shovin' it in.
Ever since then...
...when I feel like candy, I say to myself...
..."Well, you can't complain, brother."
"You once had it - and had it good."
You know what I mean?
Huh?
How's it, Molly-o?
I'm all right, thank you - but
where ya been?
What'll ya have?
Coupl'a ryes.
All day I was expectin' ya'd
be in to practise.
Practise!
I'll get down there and knock 'em dead.
It's all in the wrist, and I
got the touch, Molly.
Look at that - steady as a rock.
It'll do anything I want it to do.
Keep the change, pal.
Thanks.
You got a cigarette, Frankie?
Sure.
You're on it again, Frankie.
Why? Why?
No, now listen, Molly.
Listen.
- Why?
- Molly.
Molly.
- Not now.
- Beat it!
Molly, I... I only want to talk.
- Take a walk.
- Don't.
Molly, listen to me. I can explain.
Molly, I just wanna talk.
Will ya get outta here?
Please. Stop!
- Molly.
- Molly, listen.
- Please, will you let me---
- Please, don't hurt him, will you?
Go away!
Are you lookin' to lose your job? Can't
you manage a customer?
- Molly, listen to me.
- Let me go.
- I gotta talk to you.
- Leave me, the both of you.
Let me go, both of ya.
I can't stand it no more!
Molly!
Molly! Molly! Molly!
Molly, listen to me.
Molly, open the door!
Molly, will ya open the door?
Molly! Molly!
Let me talk to ya, Molly.
Molly!
Molly, open the door.
Molly! Honey“
Where ya goin', Molly?
Tell me - where ya goin', Molly?
Taxi!
If you let me explain, you'll
know why I did it.
Taxi!
Molly, listen, would ya, please?
Let me tell ya what happened.
Where ya goin', Molly?
Tell me, where ya goin'?
No, Molly!
Molly!
Don't forget to clean
out the gaboon.
I already cleaned it.
And say please when
ya talk to me, or I'll...
...buy a gaboon, and go into
business for myself.
How's that, Frankie?
Nuthin' huh? Well, well.
I'm reminding ya, Schwiefka.
I get two, two and a half. Maybe more.
Would I go back on my word?
How ya feelin', Dealer?
Hiya, Schwiefka.
Ah, big night, tonight.
Yeah?
This the place?
I don't know what place ya mean, Buddy.
This is the Ellis Belt and Leather Company.
Ya wanna buy a Ellis belt?
Come right in. We're just startin'.
- How ya been?
- Fine, how are you?
Pretty good.
I could handle the door
better if I was blind.
Go on, you couldn't heat towels
for a scared barber.
You know Schwiefka?
Oh, sure. Glad to have ya.
- Hi.
You Machine?
"Man with the Golden Arm", huh?
Aah! Let's see ya try and
take this away.
Here we go, down and dirty.
No ladies allowed -
you know that, Vi.
- Is Frankie in there?
- What's the matter?
Zosch - I can't get her to sleep.
She and Frankie had an argument,
and she's almost out of her mind.
Is he in there?
Well, I can't call him now.
Well, I just want to know he's here.
I been bouncin' around 12th Street
like a pool ball.
He's here. He's here.
I gotta get back in.
Well, tell him she's worried,
ya get a chance.
Yeah.
Three aces.
Two pairs.
Possible straight flush.
- Aces.
- Two hundred.
I call it two hundred.
And I'll raise it two.
I'll have a look for four hundred.
And the house bumps ya,
three hundred more.
Up to you, Aces.
I don't know. I... I just don't know.
You got three aces showin'.
He's got a possible straight
flush to the Queen showin'.
I tell ya, he's bluff in'.
I think he bluffed me outta
a couple tonight.
You wouldn't be jerk enough to
try it again, would ya?
Bet and find out.
Well, bet, bet, I tell ya -
he's a bluff-artist.
Call.
I call it.
An' I raise it five hundred more.
- Sammy!
- I know what I'm doin'.
I'll have a look.
And the house bumps ya,
five hundred more.
I told ya. I told ya he had it.
Shut up will ya, and let me think?
It's up to you.
What's the rush, I wanna know?
Your bet, two pairs.
I heard ya, I heard ya. What is this,
a forced joint or somethin'?
A man's got a right to
study his hand.
Bet or fold!
Use ya head, Sammy. I tell ya he's got it.
- Don't throw good money after bad.
- I know what I'm doin'.
What'd ya have?
You didn't pay to find out.
Nothin'!
Two lousy nines.
You let him bluff ya out of a full
house with a lousy two nines?
You do that again at this table,
and you're through.
Ah, forget it this once, Dealer.
He paid plenty for it.
You're good, Dealer.
Maybe too good.
Whaddya mean by that?
Cut the talk. Deal... deal.
Punk, get some of the
smoke outta here.
What do ya mean, "too good."?
If the shoe fits, brother.
I'm casing the deck. It's daylight.
What?
Tell him to sit down and deal.
Well, we always break
up around now.
One more round.
How about my money.
Let's have Dealer back in the slot?
- Frankie, how 'bout it'?
- Nope.
Just give me what's comin' to me.
One more hour, huh?
I'll deal.
You? We wanna play Machine.
Oh, you think I can't sell ya
a thing or two, huh?
Siddown - we'll get goin'.
- How 'bout my dough?
- Soon as we break.
Now!
Give us a chance to count it at least.
Go home, you'll get it later.
Okay, ante up. Here we go.
A hundred it is.
Yeah, a hundred.
Okay, here we go.
Good morning, Frankie.
Frankie!
Is Louie still here?
He's havin' an appleplexy. What they're
doin' to Schwiefka in there!
We're gettin' murdered - you
gotta take the slot.
I ain't here for dealin'.
Look. You gotta make it stop, Louie.
No deal, no fix.
Well, give me my money and
I'll go see someone else---
I can't give you your money now!
The house needs every cent.
You owe it to me!
- Take me to court.
- Please, Louie.
You gotta make it stop.
I'll take care of you.
Just work a few hours.
I gotta get some sleep. I gotta
be fresh tomorrow.
Work a few hours.
Do us a favour. I'll guarantee you'll
feel like a week in the country.
Please, Louie, please - now.
Drop dead!
Please. Wait a second.
Okay.
Louie says ya got money for him.
Gimme. He's waitin'!
Sparrow?
Yeah, yeah.
Yeah, I know he's waitin'.
So I seen this one and that one, and
they all say the same thing.
"Tell Louie like he tells us."
"Nothin' for nothin'."
Not a penny?
Not even.
How is it up there?
What a game.
Schwiefka's meltin' away
like a dirty candle.
The Dealer's losin', huh?
What's happened to that "golden arm"?
Don't worry about the Dealer, the game's
just goin' on a day and a half.
He'll come through.
Why not, with those educated fingers.
Now you see it - now you don't.
You keep your dirty mouth
off the Dealer.
Frankie runs a clean game.
There ain't nothin' in the world
can make him change that.
Ach!
Hey, Antek.
Deuce of hearts. Eight of spades.
All right, all right.
Six of hearts.
Well, can you let me have a thousand?
How 'bout five hundred?
- Two hundred.
- Call.
I know it's Sunday night.
I didn't call you up to
find what day it is!
House checks to you.
Here - hold it a minute.
Here, hold it.
Gimme some of that!
I gotta get outta here, Louie. I'm dead.
I ain't slept in almost two days.
Just a little while, now.
It ain't doin' ya any good.
The house is still losin'.
Stay with it, Dealer. The class is
beginning to tell. Just stay with it.
I just can't. My head won't work no more.
Louie, Louie. I'm runnin'
outta guys to call.
- Lippy?
- Can't find him.
I'll find him. He's loaded.
- I'm gettin' outta here.
- Just a little longer.
While I make a call.
Then I'll take you over to my place.
Ah, where were we. Who bets?
House checks to you.
Okay, I'll bet a hundred.
Call me.
Coffee?
Good an' black.
Schwiefka!
I can't raise another cent.
How's it goin'?
They're sluggin' us with their money.
Every pot almost, they're raisin' and
raisin', until we're forced out.
What day is it?
Can't you think of anybody we
can tap for a few thousand?
What day is it? Is it Monday yet?
Listen to me.
Are you listenin' to me?
Why--- What?
Listen to me, I said.
The next big pot they try to force you out
with a raise - you gotta stay with 'em.
Schwiefka don't let me. He
keeps nudging me to fold.
That's cause he ain't sure you'll win.
You can't be sure.
There's a way you can
be sure, all right.
You can do anything you
want with those cards.
Ah, that's only for fun, I haven't
got nerve to do it for real.
You wanna get outta here, don't ya?
What?
You wanna get to that try-out
in good condition, don't ya?
Yeah, I wanna get there feelin' good.
Well, you make sure - you
know what I mean?
Let's get on with the game.
Let's get on with the game - I feel hot.
Yeah.
Wanna play again?
Yeah, might as well sit in one.
Okay, Dealer.
I'm in.
Three. King.
Jack.
Queen bets a honey.
Call.
Ah... pair a treys.
King, ten, Jack. seven. Pair of treys.
I bet two hundred.
I call it two.
House bets two.
Comm' out.
Pair of treys, pair of Kings,
pair of jacks.
I'm bettin' five hundred.
House sees.
Call.
Comm' out.
Three treys, Kings, Jacks, three treys.
Three little treys bet five
hundred bucks.
Why, you! Cheatin', huh?
Take off your glasses.
- No.
- Take 'em off!
- I didn't know, I didn't know!
- I'll get to you in a second.
I didn't know!!! This has never
happened before!
Eleven years I've been runnin'
this game - ask anybody!
You don't deal for me no more.
You want him?
I wouldn't dirty my hands.
How was I to know?
You fellas, you fellas - do I
ever rig an honest game?
Tell 'em, tell em'.
Frankie?
Everything's all right now, Frankie.
Hey... Frankie... what's a little cuff in' around,
huh? Nothin'. Am I right?
You'll see - an hour from now we'll be in
Antek's, just laughin' about it.
You shoulda seen Schwiefka's face...
...when Williams said he'll
"get to him in a minute".
He went white. It was so funny.
Cut it out, d'you hear?
It was the best sport I knew,
my whole life.
Do you hear me?
Get away from me, punk.
- Hurry, quick.
- I wanna get to sleep.
Please - wait.
Beginning to wear off quick for you, ain't
it? You're graduating, student.
- You're gonna have to step it up.
- Anything. But, please - hurry.
All right.
Let's see your money.
Later, later.
Right now.
- Trust me this once, will ya?
- You know I don't do that.
I'll pay you twice as much later, but I
gotta' do somethin' right now.
Beat it.
I'll even push for you, Louie. Hurry.
A flippin' junkie always says that.
Please, Louie - please. Please, Louie!
Get your dirty hands off!
Frankie.
- Wake up! Get up!
- No, No.
- Where'd you put it?
- Frankie. No!
- No, no Frankie, let go.
- Where'd ya keep it!
I gotta find it. I can't find it!
Frankie, let me take you home. Frankie,
please - let me take ya home.
Frankie. Frankie, please!
I gotta be on time. I gotta be on time.
Frankie.
Wow! What's the matter? Come on -
let's try to really cook it.
Mr Machine.
Mr Lane.
Okay, can you read music?
Yes.
Shelley - let Mr Machine
sit in on this one.
Number thirty-seven - it's
right in front of you.
You know it, Mr Machine?
Okay, let's try it.
One-two-three-four.
Mr Machine - the first four bars is all you.
C'mon, let's try it again.
One-two-three-four.
I'm sorry.
Are you all set? Once again,
one-two-three-four!
Okay, Shelley - let's go.
Zosch - do we have any money?
I need some money.
No. What's the matter?
Some around here yesterday,
wasn't there?
I need some money, Zosch.
Well, there ain't any. What is
it, Frankie? What is it?
You can walk. Since when?
Well, what's the angle?
What are you and Frankie
tryin' to pull?
Come on - tell me, one
hustler to another, huh?
Go on - let me in on it?
Let me in on it or I'll queer
it for you, ya hear'?
I'll tell everybody you can walk -
you always could.
I'll tell 'em all you can walk -
you're a phoney!
No! Louie, Louie. Louie, no,
no - you can't do that.
You can't tell anybody! Please, Louie!
- Let me be!
- Please, Louie.
- Get your hands off.
- No!
Don't touch him.
Call the police.
Molly! Molly! Molly!
Ain't that the way it happened?
They had a fight. Next thing anyone
knew, Louie was falling.
Come on - level, Zosch. Don't
tryta out-think me.
You'll only get tangled.
I don't know anythin' about a fight.
I... I was sleepin' all morning,
right here in this chair.
Then for all ya know, it
did happen that way?
While you was sleepin', Frankie
shoved him over.
He didn't.
How do you know, if you was sleepin'?
It wasn't like I was sleepin' -
more like dozin', kinda'.
I'd have heard a fight
if there was one.
Frankie didn't do it - he
wasn't even here.
- When wasn't he here?
- When it happened.
How can you be sure
if you was dozin'?
I... I was up when he left, that's how
I'm sure I saw him go.
Then he was home this mornin'?
But only a second, honest.
He didn't get in a fight. He
was here only a second.
Why didn't he stick around?
Was somebody after him?
Nobody was after him - nobody. He
just wanted some money, is all.
What for?
I don't know what for.
A fix. He wanted it for a fix from Louie.
It had nothing to do with Louie.
How do you know?
'Cos there was no money.
Why would he want to see Louie for a
fix, if he didn't have no money?
To try and get one without money.
Okay, I can wait. Wherever he is...
...sooner or later, he's gotta'
come out for a fix.
Molly. Molly, wait, please.
It's finished, Frankie - like I told ya.
I gotta talk to you, Molly. Please.
No, once and for all.
I gotta talk to you. Got any money,
Molly? I need a few dollars.
Ten dollars would do it.
I'll get it back to you in a few days.
Or five, even. Five would be fine.
Please. I feel so sick, Molly. I... I
hurt all over, I feel so bad.
Don't say no, please don't say no.
Why not, Molly? Why not?
Jump off a roof if you gonna kill yourself,
but don't ask me to help ya.
I'll do anything for you, Molly, but... but
right now you gotta help me.
I... I need a shot.
No!
Five would do it, or... three or two,
even - but please, hurry.
You mustn't take that
dirty stuff no more!
I know, I know - you're right...
and I promise.
But right now I need a fix.
Just one fix - to help me stop hurtin'.
And then I promise you I'll
kick it for good.
Just a few dollars, Molly? Please!
Hello, Molly. I just wanted
to come say "hello".
Ain't ya gonna let me in?
I asked you please not to
bother me no more.
I... I miss you.
Look - I'm awfully tired, Johnny.
I'll stay only a few minutes.
No.
Who's in there with you?
Go away, Johnny - and don't come back.
Who is it? Not the Dealer? You
ain't hidin' him, are ya?
You wouldn't be dumb enough to
be an accessory, would you?
What do you mean, "accessory"?
He killed Louie.
Cops are lookin' for him this minute!
Frankie Machine?
Is he in there?
No.
I'm comin' in.
Not if you ever want
to see me again.
Will you meet me tomorrow?
Yeah. Yeah, I'll be around Antek's.
Maybe not tomorrow - but soon.
I miss ya.
Honest, I... I didn't.
What am I gonna do?
Go tell Bednar it wasn't you.
L...l couldn't. I couldn't stand up
to the cops the way I am.
Look at me. I'd say anything they'd want
me to say, just for a shot.
Then get cured first.
What are you talkin' about'? How am
I supposed to get cured?
You did it once.
That was with help and
medicine - and doctors.
I can't go applying to Lexington with a
murder hangin' over my head.
Couldn't you do it without goin' there?
You mean just stop?
Cold turkey?
You don't understand,
the... pain.
What else can you do?
All I need is one shot - just one.
All right!
It's here - take it.
Go on and take it all.
'Cos all that you're gonna need after
that one shot - is another.
And then another, and then another.
Take it!
Why should you hurt like
other people hurt?
Yes, so you had a dog's life,
with never a break.
Why try to face it - like
most people do?
No - just roll up all your pains...
...into one big hurt - and then
flatten it with a fix.
What d'ya think you'll find
just outside that door?
Don't ya think that Bednar
knows what ya are...
...and what ya need... just to get
through that next hour?
Don't ya know he's just waitin'
for ya to come and get it?
Go on! Let him kill ya!
Let him kill ya! It'll be quicker and
better than doin' it your way.
No.
I won't let him kill me.
And I won't run into no grave.
But... kickin' it?!
Look... a guy can't do it by himself.
I'll help.
You know what you're
letting yourself in for?
It ain't pretty... and it could
be dangerous.
If they find ya here, then
they find ya, is all.
I don't mean dangerous from Bednar.
I mean dangerous from me.
Sometimes a junkie will... kill to get
away from the treatment.
Understand?
So if you've got any knives
or scissors in the house...
...you've gotta... put 'em
away for a while.
And don't let me out of the room.
No matter what I say or promise -
or how much I beg.
Because if I get out, it'll only be
to go out and find a fix.
That's the way it is, ya understand?
Just lock me in the room.
And if I try to make a break for it, stop
me any way ya know how.
No matter how much
you see it hurtin' me...
...don't try to help me with pills or dope
or anything else like that.
D'you think you can handle it...?
Here we go...
...down and dirty.
You can't hold me. You're commitin'
double jeopardy or somethin'.
Siddown.
You can't hold me.
I ain't got all my marbles -
you know that, Captain.
Right - down to cases, Sparrow.
And quit horsin' around.
I didn't do nothin'.
Frankie did somethin', all right - and I
want you to tell me about it.
Whoever killed that peddler should
get a tickertape parade!
Yeah, and maybe I'd lead the band - but
I still want ya to tell me about it.
Listen to me, Sparrow - when we
catch him, he stands trial...
...whether you talk or whether you don't.
The only question is - do I ticket
you as an accessory?
Bednar - don't nail me to the cross.
He's the only guy I ever
had for a friend.
He's nobody's friend anymore.
He'd mash you with a steamroller if you
got between him and a pop in the arm.
Come on - talk, Sparrow.
Okay - beat it.
Doc...
...Lennox!
DRAMATIC MUSIC]
Lemme out!
Come on, Moll!!!
C'mon!!
Yes?
I thought I'd come see how
you've been, Zosch.
Alone - that's how I've been.
Something to eat - sausage.
Alone and worried sick. Where is he?
You know where he is?
Did he go to you?
Whaddya want, anyway?
Zosch, what you told Bednar.
You've seen the papers.
You see how bad it makes Frankie
look, what ya said.
I didn't tell Bednar anything. The papers -
they twist everything all up.
They wouldn't be able to
if ya didn't let them.
I can't help what they do.
Whaddya expect me to do, sittin' here?
Just tell Bednar that Frankie wasn't
here when it happened.
That he didn't do it.
I never said he did.
But that's how it sounds, if he was the
only one around at the time!
And you know it was somebody else.
What do you mean? Who?
I don't know, but maybe Bednar
could figure it out...
...if he didn't think it was Frankie.
What business is it of yours, anyway?
I just wanna help, that's all.
Who are you kiddin'?
You think I don't know
what you really want.
You think I don't know what you and him
have been up to behind my back...
...while I've had to sit here
all these years?
Had to sit here all these years!
No, Zosch - you got it wrong.
No - you got it wrong! 'Cos
you'll never get him.
He put me in this chair - and as long
as I sit here he'll never leave me.
He knows he belongs to me.
- No, Zosch, I come here only to help.
- I wouldn't want to live if he left me.
And I'd rather see him dead, too,
than have him go to you.
Zosch, please.
Get outta here!
Get outta here, ya lousy tramp!
Get out!
Get out!!!
Frankie, no!
I can't stand it any longer.
- Just a little longer.
- Please help me'? Keep me warm.
I can't stand it.
I gotta get out... and get a fix.
Open the door, Molly - do like I say.
Open the door or I'll kill ya! I'll kill ya!
- Frankie, listen. If you really---
- I can't, I can't!
Then I do have something put
away to make it stop.
Gimme, quick. Gimme, quick!
Where?! I'll get it.
Molly! Molly, open the door! Let
me out! Out! Out!
Out, out, out!!
Molly, open the door!
Please Molly! Molly! Molly!
Frankie?
Frankie, answer me.
Are ya all right?
Don't think you can fool me into opening
this door, 'cause I'm not gonna.
Are y'all right, Frankie?
Please answer me.
Molly... Molly - if you love me,
kill me. Please.
Oh, I'm so cold. I'm so cold.
So cold.
Make me warm, please?
Oh, please warm me.
Molly...
Please, Molly - make me warm.
Oh, Molly - I'm so c-c-cold.
Make me warm?
Oh, God, God. Please, God.
Please make me warm, Molly.
I'm so c-c-cold.
So cold.
I waited for ya at Antek's last night.
I told ya it might not be right away.
I... I thought maybe you were
sick or somethin'.
I... I just wanna' tell ya - don't look
for me in Antek's no more.
He threw me out last night-
we had a little argument.
So make it the Safari, huh?
Yeah. Sure, Johnny - sure.
Pretty good, huh, Molly?
Take it slow, now.
Oh, I'm all right. Just a little rocky.
It's the most gorgeous day
I ever saw.
I think it's the first day
I gotta craving for something sweet.
You got anything sweet?
- Sugar.
- Gimme.
More. C'mon - more.
Ooh! How can you, Frankie?
Oh, I never felt this good in my life.
I feel like all the things inside me
have settled into place.
Thanks, Molly.
Molly-o.
Look out - you'll scrape your face off.
I don't care.
- You got a razor I can use?
- Can I trust you with one?
Cross my heart.
- Is this the place?
- Yeah.
Okay. Come on.
No, please.
You don't need me up there.
Where is he, Molly?
He didn't do it - honest.
I'm not a judge. They pay me
to bring 'em in, that's all.
If you tell me where he is...
...I promise he'll get every break
a junkie can get.
He's no junkie, either.
That's finished.
Oh, sure - you bet.
See for yourself.
He ain't runnin' away from ya.
So, where is he?
With Zosch.
All right, Molly. Let's go see.
Hello, Zosch.
What are ya doin' here?
Frankie - don't you know
Bednar's lookin' for ya?
Don't worry about it, Zosch, I ain't afraid.
I didn't do it - you know that.
Who... Who did, then?
Who?
I come to tell ya somethin', Zosch.
I'm leavin' here.
Bednar will arrest you. He told
the newspapers you---
What?
I'm leaving.
You won't have to worry about
money or anything;
I'll find a way to send you some regular.
And Vi'll take good care of ya.
Leaving me!?
Not leavin' you, Zosch -
just leavin'.
You saw what happened since I come back.
It's like Dr Lennox told me.
I got in the same old routine and...
...before I knew it I was on it again.
But you can't leave me!
You... you gotta stay and
take care of me.
I know I'm responsible for
how y'are, Zosch.
But I can't go around
the rest of my life...
...stoning myself to death about it.
I've been carrying my heart
ever since it happened.
Even now it hurts me to
think about it.
But...
...well - it's not I wanna leave.
I gotta leave.
You mustn't leave. Frankie!
You mustn't leave!
Zosch...
...say good-bye to me, Zosch.
You think you're foolin' me? I know what's
pullin' ya away - Molly!
No.
You're only goin' just so you can
be with that little tramp!
- Frankie, no!
- Goodbye, Zosch.
No, Frankie! Please don't leave.
Frankie - no. No, don't leave me!
Get dressed, Zosch.
Zosch!
Zosch!!!
Zosch?
Zosch, don't move.
Don't try to talk - you're
gonna' be all right.
I love you so much. So---
Zosch.